Carol...
Mr. Vice President...
Mind your manners.
I'm sorry! I just got carried away.
What were you doing?
I was thinking about this story.
Story?
Yes. The series of strange tales
that started in November of 1930.
Once, we traveled together
on a train, didn't we, Carol?
Do you remember what
I said to you at the time?
Let's see...
Wow! A rainbow!
Carol...
From the time that we were children,
we have thought of rainbows
as being beautiful things,
without any doubts at all.
Why is that?
People who do not know
about the refraction of light
may also think of it as a
harbinger of a natural disaster.
Something unwelcome might be
coming down through that rainbow.
The vegetation may be burning
up at the base of that rainbow.
Why is it that we feel a sense of fairy tales
from that bit of seven-colored information?
Have you ever thought about that?
No.
I mean, even if
I did think about it, I couldn't tell,
and besides, our job is
not to think about things,
but to report to others the
outcome of what has already happened.
319 points.
Out of how many?
It's true, our job is to
convey the truth to others,
but the moment that we obtain any
information, be it truth or falsehood,
we must not stop thinking.
We must not stop at just determining
whether the information is true or false.
Such is the responsibility of those
who deliver information to others.
But, what is there to think about?
Just thinking about something doesn't
change whether or not it's true, right?
Yes, it does change.
Do you remember, Carol?
Yes, Mr. Vice President.
A story is neither information,
nor is it accumulated information.
It is the result of what has been thought.
Carol, why did you think that these
stories started in November, 1930?
Well...
What's the matter, Carol?
And you call yourself the assistant
to Gustave Saint-Germain,
Vice President of the Daily Days?
Well, I...
Let's say, Carol...
It is 1711,
and it would be best to start inside
the Advenna A vis, as it crosses the Atlantic.
Or, perhaps,
it might be best to start
with the nasty business
that happened aboard the
transcontinental Flying Pussyfoot,
which was covered up.
Either way, Carol,
you have chosen November of 1930
as the start of the story.
Why is that?
Mr. Vice President, it's because...
It's because, you see, I thought about
what would be easiest to understand.
It was at that point when these
incidents first came before our eyes.
That's why.
156 points.
Out of how many?
Indeed, it is easier to understand.
But Carol,
you should think about
more than just the time axis.
The characters are also crucial.
Let's say...
Yow!
Isaac!
What if we were to look at
that eccentric pair of robbers
as being the main characters?
Or, perhaps,
the young lad,
suffering with a cursed destiny?
Or, perhaps,
the Gandor Family's brilliant young capo?
Or, perhaps...
If that's what you mean...
Charity? Please, do you
have any charity to offer?
The Lord is watching your actions.
In time, the Lord will judge your actions...
Old-timer...
He seems main-characterish.
"-ish"?
Yes. "-ish."
I'm in a good mood today.
Take it.
Thank you very much, sir!
The Lord is sure to bless your actions!
Quit being so pious only
when it suits you, old-timer.
Just a moment, sir.
I have some flowers I picked
this morning, to thank you.
They're probably wilted anyhow.
I'm not so sure about that... sir!
Well, he's pretty close, isn't he?
Say, tell me something...
Stay back, you monster!
Did you know that I was Firo
Prochainezo, of the Martillo Family,
old-timer?!
I see now!
"Main-characterish."
You may indeed be right about that.
Aren't I?
Still, Carol, depending
upon whom you focus on,
the same incident switches
form in an ever-changing manner.
In other words, there is one incident,
but there are as many stories
about it as there are people involved.
Listen up, men!
Destroy everything!
No need for warnings or negotiating!
Now, it's our time!
Nobody else exists in our world!
Gandors, Martillos, it doesn't matter!
Crush them till there's nothing left!
Make it as though
they utterly never existed!
So, what became of that idiot, Luck?
Chick-san is handling him.
He's seeing if he still has enough
sensitivity left to feel any pain.
Boss, they got us again!
What's the damage?
A gambling parlor, a bar,
and a ticket window.
Luckily, nobody is dead.
Those Runoratas!
I'm gonna blow them away!
Clobber them! And kill them dead!
We dragged back one of the guys
that went after the ticket window.
All right...
You're the villain that
came after our turf, are you?!
You've got a lot of spunk, huh?
So you're saying, it starts when the Mafia
and the Camorra go after each other?
In one instance.
Luck Gandor has been put to sleep.
Word was that he was pretty capable,
but it was child's play.
The Gandors are
a small-time outfit, anyway.
It won't take much trouble
to wipe them out.
We've made arrangements to purchase
some newer, special bombs from certain sources,
so in time, we'll also round up the Martillos.
Never mind that.
There's something that I need you to do.
Or, perhaps...
Big Brother Dallas...
Where are you?
Or perhaps, Carol,
it wouldn't be too surprising for us
to be the ones at the start of this story.
We couldn't be!
Dallas Genoard. You know him, right?
Yeah. He's the second son
of the Genoard family.
He's the son of Raymond Genoard,
whom you killed on your own,
without instructions from me.
Dallas Genoard is
the younger brother of Geoffrey Genoard,
whom you also killed on your own.
You follow?
Yeah. So what about Dallas?
He contacted the office.
He said that you're the one
who killed his father and brother, Gustavo.
He also says that he has proof.
T-That can't be right.
I even paid off the court officers.
There's no way there's any proof.
Then how is it that Dallas named you?
Well...
Deal with it.
Find him, and bring him here.
Y-Yes, sir.
But what about the Gandors?
Dallas has first priority.
Find him as soon as possible.
Y-Yes, sir.
Do I get to decide
whether he comes in dead or alive?
Dead or alive?
Suit yourself.
Listen up, men! Get Dallas!
Find that despicable
second son of the Genoards!
Dead or alive!
He's going to pay for
making a fool of me, Gustavo,
What a wretched man.
and the entire Runorata Family!
Say something!
Where's the nerve you had
when you attacked our territory?!
You were ready to answer
for this, weren't you?!
"Ugghh"? Don't you "ugghh" me!
I said say something!
Why are you...
You look like you've seen a ghost.
You're... supposed to be dead...
Chick-san! Chick-san!
Yes? What is it, Luck-san?
I need to ask you to do one more.
Very well.
But I haven't washed off
the blood and grease from the last one yet.
So I think it's going to hurt an awful lot.
Sorry about that.
P-Please, wait!
I'll tell you anything! I'll tell you!
Just don't let that freak near me!
Who was it that turned me into a honeycomb?
Luck...
Firo...
You look creepy when you smirk like that.
What are you reading?
"Thy soul shall find itself alone
'Mid dark thoughts of the grey tomb-stone;
Not one, of all the crowd, to pry
Into thine hour of secrecy."
Long ago, I was so scared of this poem,
I couldn't stand it.
But that's not the case now.
Not since the incident a year ago.
Why is that?
Maybe because as much as
I've lost any need to be afraid,
I've also lost any feelings of anxiety.
Towards death, I mean.
Firo, don't you think anything of it?
Nope.
Forget about it, please.
Be that as it may,
there's been an unusual bunch that
has been hanging around on our turf lately.
Probably some guys who
have the Runoratas backing them.
I'll be there to help you,
whenever it hits the fan.
Firo, please, pretend you don't know.
This is our problem.
That's a pretty standoffish thing to ask.
I'm not going to put the Martillos out.
Don't worry. We've called in Vino.
Vino? Claire is coming in?
Arriving on the Flying Pussyfoot tomorrow.
In that case, Isaac and Miria
are on the same train.
One of Maiza-san's old friends is aboard, too.
Then, let's go pick them up together-
And you're certain?
Yes. The damage is severe,
but there's no mistake that they were
passengers aboard the Flying Pussyfoot.
How many bodies does that make?
The number we've discovered
is somewhere in the teens.
They've been left along the side of the tracks
here and there over several dozen kilometers.
Inspectors, what on earth happened here?
The matter is classified.
You're better off not knowing.
Looks like they were aboard, all right.
Immortals?
Yeah.
Their names were on the passenger list
at the station in Chicago.
What about the lady's safety?
Our orders are to investigate that next.
You think we can keep
an incident like this covered up?
Inspector Sullivan...
What?
There appears to be a survivor
among the passengers that fell out.
What?!
L-Luck-san...
Hey. Are you hurt?
Y-You just got shot up!
There's no problem, right?
Ee-yow!
Huh?
It doesn't hurt.
Isaac! Your wound has disappeared!
That's an incredible trick!
Maybe doves will appear next!
He's so useless.
There's no way you can still be alive...
Firo!
Firo, where are you?!
Right here.
This can't be!
At least let me do this much.
I'll pay for the damages.
So what you saw here today...
N-Not at all!
I didn't see anything!
Besides, if I ever did tell anyone,
they'd put me in a sanatorium, at best!
Still...
it doesn't look like we can ignore this.
I'll find you.
I promise.
The Flying Pussyfoot
is quite an unusual train, huh?
I've seen it once before and
it's overly ornamental, to put it one way.
If I had to say, it looks kind of ostentatious.
I want to see it even more, now.
That's too bad.
There was an announcement a moment ago
that the Flying Pussyfoot had a breakdown,
and all the passenger cars were
switched to another train.
Huh?! Are you serious?!
Either way, the lead car will
be switched with a smokeless,
electric engine before it enters Manhattan,
so you won't be
able to see the whole thing.
Maybe so, but...
Oh, by the way, what kind of person
is this old friend of yours, Maiza-san?
Ah, yes...
He tries to carry everything on his
shoulders, despite being so introverted.
That's the type of person he is.
The type who wouldn't last long,
were they a normal person, huh?
Claire is the same way,
for the opposite reason.
Cheerful, but far too obstinate.
That's the truth.
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey!
Would you decide whether you're just gonna stare,
or if you're gonna take me in?
Despite appearances,
I'm in a pretty foul mood.
If I'd known this would happen,
I would have killed you sooner.
Or would you like me to kill you, right here?
But, Ladd...
What's wrong?
You saying you don't wanna be killed by me?!
It hurts! It hurts! Just a minute...
I'm sorry, Nice... Please,
can we go a little slower?
Hey!
Hey there!
Oh! Ennis, Firo, and Maiza!
Long time no see, my fine fellows!
I'm so glad to see you're all doing so well!
You too, Isaac-san and Miria-san.
We're doing fine!
What happened? You look like hell-
Live long enough,
and I'll tell you someday!
It's been too long!
Looking up at the starry sky
that goes on forever, we sing
a melody of a dream
we have of our limited eternity
The water of adoration,
overflowing in our hearts
will reach someone in the distant future
I believe so
Running through time prolonged,
our voices calling out will
someday become a great song
We can go on spinning our love
though it may still be such a tiny light now
Hey, Miria,
where could this "aside"place be?
It means not at home, right?
Which means that it's somewhere
not at home, right?
Then, where is "somewhere"?
I'm sure it's aside, where
the old woman's qualms are.
That's incredible, Isaac! You're so smart!