Sam?
Why don't you go ahead?
I'm gonna share a poem
I've been working on.
I don't want to, but Reuben
said I had to, so...
I didn't say you had to.
It's called
"This Place is Shit."
Oh, good.
"This place is shit.
This place smells like shit.
Betsy's voice sounds like shit.
Cancer is shit.
Oscar does that stupid walk
When he wants to hide
he shit his pants.
And Milton has
shit taste in music."
It's not finished.
That was great.
That was great. Let's...
- I'm gonna clap for that.
- Don't clap for it.
I'm gonna clap for it.
Clap for it.
I smell smoke.
It's okay, everyone.
- How's your pain?
- Great.
Thanks for sharing today. Uh...
Lot of profanity, but I, um,
I didn't appreciate the comment
about Oscar's poop-walk.
- Oscar thought it was funny.
- It was funny,
- but it was still mean.
- I'm a very mean person.
- That's a very open realization.
- I've known that for a while.
Hey! We're going to a show.
Half an hour.
Oh, see,
I might be dead by then.
Oh, yeah, you might.
But if you're not dead,
it's short
and it's in the city.
When's the last time
you were in the city?
Last time was supposed
to be the last time.
Well, here's another time.
I'll go if we get pizza.
Didn't we have pizza
yesterday?
- Did you eat it?
- No.
That wasn't pizza.
Okay, well, then, yeah, we'll
get pizza on the way back.
In the city.
- I'll go get changed.
- All right.
Let Katie know
if you need help!
Yeah.
Quiet.
You're getting fat.
Thank you so much.
All right, guys,
this is a little bit steep.
So grab onto the railing
if you need help.
Um, and remember,
go bad leg first.
It's a puppet show.
It's a marionette show.
We are the marionette club.
- You lied.
- I don't know if I lied.
You could've checked
the schedule.
You tricked.
Oh, yeah,
I tricked you for sure.
Marionettes have
a fascinating history.
The word's actually
a reference to the Virgin Mary.
Osa.
- Sorry about that.
- It's fine.
This is Frodo.
Hi, Frodo.
Osa, turn around.
Hi!
- Just this?
- Just this.
How much do I owe you?
Hey. How much?
It's four dollars.
And you can't
have a cat in here.
It's a service cat.
No, I hear you.
I'll gather them all up
and get them on the bus
as soon as I can.
Hello?
Hello? Shit!
You okay?
Oh. Yeah. Um...
Yeah, I just...
How's your pain?
- Three?
- Okay.
So, listen, uh,
we have to head back now.
Why?
Something's happening
in the city
and they want us back ASAP.
But we're
getting pizza first.
No, we're gonna have to
rain check the pizza.
They can wait,
it's just pizza.
Sam, we'll get pizza
another day, okay?
We're already in the city.
Well, then we'll
order it tonight.
- Just get it in the city.
- What?
We're getting pizza in the city
and then we'll go back.
- No, we're not getting pizza.
- Yes, we are getting pizza.
- Okay, you got to calm down.
- Don't tell me to calm down.
I don't want to argue with you.
I'm your friend, okay?
You're not my friend.
You're a nurse.
- I'm getting on the bus.
- Yeah, get on the bus.
I'm s...
Use that one.
Good leg goes up.
Can you walk?
I got you. I got you.
It was like
a flash and then...
Ma'am! Ma'am!
Take cover! Now!
They're fucking everywhere!
Run! Run!
Shh! Shh!
Shelter in place.
Remain silent.
Attackers are deadly.
Make no sound.
Wait for
further instructions.
Attackers are deadly.
Remain silent.
Minus 73.949708 west.
I repeat. Minus 73.949708 west.
Evacuate the area.
- Sorry.
- I repeat.
Remain silent
and evacuate the area.
This is not a drill.
Evacuate immediately.
At 2100 hours,
all civilians
on Manhattan bridges
will be in active...
What's happening?
We're trapped. We're trapped!
- We're all gonna die...
- Shh!
Shh!
Look what they're doing!
Stop.
We're all gonna die!
I'm sorry.
No.
I'm going.
Stay. Stay.
Boat evacuations
are beginning now
at the South Street Seaport.
Travel south
with extreme caution.
Come with me.
You have to be very quiet,
okay? Come on.
This is
a mandatory evacuation order.
We remain under attack.
Seek shelter on water.
The attackers cannot swim.
Boat evacuations
are beginning now
at the South Street Seaport.
Go.
Please! Please!
- Please! Help me!
- Shh!
Help! Help me!
Jonathan? Jonathan!
Hey.
What's your name?
Talk under
the rain. What's your name?
Eric.
Eric? Okay, Eric.
You need to go
to the South Street Seaport.
There are boats there, okay?
Okay.
Okay. Okay.
- Eric?
- Okay.
- Hey.
You need to stop
following me, okay?
Okay.
- That way?
- Yeah.
Okay.
Okay. Okay. Okay.
I'm really scared.
I don't want to die here.
Okay.
Look.
Let's just get out
of the rain, okay?
Okay.
Come on.
- Is this your place?
- Yeah.
Kick it down.
Kick it down with
your foot.
Wait.
- What are you doing?
- I'm looking for my meds.
Why are you looking
for your meds?
Because every muscle
in my body is on fire!
Eric,
do you have family here?
Why?
Don't you have
anywhere you can go?
No.
My parents are in Kent.
In England.
I came here for law school.
That was the one thing
I was supposed to do.
You got to get to the water
and get out of the city.
- Where are you going?
- I'm going to get pizza.
Where?
Patsy's up in Harlem.
I think the world
might be ending.
And I think there's
a slice of Patsy's
sitting up there that's
the last that'll ever exist.
And I'm gonna get it.
Okay.
Okay, what?
Okay, let's get pizza.
No, I'm getting pizza.
- Did you write this?
- Yeah.
You're a poet?
Not anymore.
Who's that?
That's my dad.
He played piano?
He played
beautiful piano.
This wasn't part
of the plan.
Please, can I come
and get pizza with you?
Read this.
"Bad Math.'
You said one to two years.
And it has been two.
You said four to six months,
And it has been six.
And Mrs. Friedlander taught
Me subtraction,
And the corner store
Taught me addition,
And I used only simple maths
All my life.
And I never needed more
Than more,
And less.
To four.
To three.
To smaller
And smaller.
Until months,
To days.
To hours,
To seconds.
But to not now.'"
You're good. You're good.
Hey...
It's okay. It's okay.
It's okay?
It's okay.
It's okay. It's okay.
It's fine.
No, no, no.
I'm here.
My father
played beautiful piano.
I loved...
when he took me
to see him play.
At a jazz club
by Patsy's.
Then after,
we'd get pizza.
Pizza.
What happened to him?
He died.
Like I am now.
Not before we get pizza.
Where did
your dad play piano?
Breathe.
Run.
Stop the boat.
Stop the boat!
You can do it! Come on!
You're safe.
Safe.
Eric,
you better take care of my cat.
Don't rub his belly.
He doesn't like that.
And don't feed him too much.
He'll get fat.
And thank you.
Thank you for bringing me home.
Thank you for helping me
live again.
I had forgotten
how the city sings.
You can hear it
when you're quiet.
♪ It's a new dawn
It's a new day ♪
♪ It's a new life for me
Yeah ♪
♪ It's a new dawn
It's a new day ♪
It's good
to have been back.
♪ Ooh, ooh, ooh, ooh, ooh... ♪
♪ And I'm feeling good ♪
♪ Fish in the sea
You know how I feel ♪
♪ River running free
♪ Blossom on the tree
You know how I feel ♪
♪ It's a new dawn
It's a new day ♪
♪ It's a new life for me ♪
♪ And I'm feeling good ♪
♪ Dragonfly out in the sun ♪
♪ You know what I mean
Don't you know? ♪
♪ Butterflies all havin' fun ♪
♪ You know what I mean ♪
♪ Sleep in peace
When day is done ♪
♪ That's what I mean ♪
♪ And this old world
Is a new world ♪
♪ And a bold world, for me ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah ♪
♪ Stars when you shine
You know how I feel ♪
♪ Scent of the pine
♪ Oh, freedom is mine ♪
♪ And I know how I feel ♪
♪ It's a new dawn
It's a new day ♪
♪ It's a new life for me ♪
♪ Oh, I'm feeling good ♪