My lords and ladies!
Today, your Queen will
choose her champion.
Here he will battle
for not only her honor,
but for a title of his own.
But only if he can defeat
the Captain of my Guard,
Sir Horace the Black!
Sir William, wouldst
thou fight for my honor?
To the death, Your Majesty.
Let's hope it does
not come to that, eh?
I choose Sir William
as my champion.
Attack from his left side.
I saw his squire bandaging
that shoulder this morning.
I wish thee luck and strength.
I fear I shall
need all I can get.
The Captain of my Guard,
Sir Horace the Black!
Are you sure you wouldn't like to
reconsider your choice, my Queen?
I believe I chose
rightly, my King.
Brave knights, in the honored
tradition of our land, have at ye!
I fear you chose
most poorly, my love.
William! William!
William? What is it?
Your eyes.
William.
We need an ambulance
at the Camden Fairgrounds.
You're new.
You're naked.
And for the record,
a little bit cold.
I'm sorry, I didn't know
that anyone was home.
James had an early call,
and I was just leaving.
Without breakfast?
I'm fine, thanks.
I'm Sam, by the way.
House. Nice to meet you.
It'd be nicer if
you put this on.
So you and Wilson...
Thought you were staying
in New York last night.
Sorry, must have missed the "if
this trailer be a-rocking" sign out front.
I'm really late, so...
If there's any chance that we
can pretend this never happened,
I'd be completely
fine with that.
An eight-year-old
with bleeding ears.
I'll see your bleeding ears and raise
you a total muscular degeneration.
What the hell?
I had a dream like this
once. It didn't end well.
Huzzah, my loyal peasants.
House, what are you doing?
Filling in for Rabbi Shmuhl
at the Goldstein Bris.
While I'm busy, you all can check
out the knight down in the ER,
who instead of seizing
the throne, just seized.
He works at a
Renaissance festival?
Doesn't work
there, he lives there.
He's part of a
wonderful little troupe
who spend their weekends
re-enacting a nobler age
when people crapped in the streets and
Thirteen would've been a grandmother.
Weeks, not weekends. Says here
he's been camping out for a month.
Try doing that with a pen.
Why don't you put that down
before you kill one of us?
Better idea. Why don't you
give me something I can use
so I won't feel the need to?
Seizure right after a fight
obviously suggests concussion.
Obviously it isn't, or the ER
wouldn't have called House.
A full suit of armor would
protect against visible trauma,
but not transmitted
concussive force.
Could be a subdural hematoma.
You're forgetting to demonize.
An evil, satanic
subdural hematoma.
No, two demon eyes.
Hemorrhaging in the sclerae.
Could be an allergic reaction to
something from the Renaissance fair.
Which is why we need
to check out Middle Earth.
Foreman, take Frodo and
break bread with the Hobbits.
I still think a hematoma
is more likely.
That's why you and Chase
are gonna get an MRI.
But you just...
I said Frodo, not Gollum.
Is he saying I have
short legs or hairy feet?
I don't even know who Frodo is.
Who's the chick, and
why are you hiding her?
You were home last night?
And this morning. I bumped
into your babe naked.
I told you to stay
out of my bathroom.
I was in the kitchen.
She was naked in the
kitchen? I was naked.
Why were you
naked in the kitchen?
That's not important right now.
What is, is why you didn't want
me to meet her in the first place.
Is she married? No.
Patient?
I don't have time for this.
She used to be a man. House!
She wants to be a man.
Sam is a man's
name, short for...
Samantha.
The soulless harpy you
were married to before we met.
People change, House.
Sure. They get older,
their ovaries start drying up
and nice guys like you
look attractive again.
Listen, I know that in
your own demented way,
you think you're looking
out for me. But I have this.
By "this" you mean a sinking
feeling in the pit of the stomach.
Fine, I get it.
It's your life, you go
screw it up. I can wait.
For what?
To tell you, "I told you so."
No signs of a hematoma.
Brain looks completely normal.
Normal, except for the fact
that he likes to play dress-up.
My uncle used to pretend
that he was King Leopold.
I'm not pretending.
Sorry about that.
But you don't really think
you're a knight, do you?
Being a knight isn't
a game, it's a lifestyle,
and we do it every day, not
just when we play dress-up.
We live by a code, and uphold
ideals like loyalty, courage, humility.
And the part where you beat the
crap out of each other in armor?
That we do for fun. At least
it was up until yesterday.
Are we almost
done? I'm feeling...
Let's get him out of
there before he aspirates.
Anything abnormal on the MRI?
God's teeth! What strange
manner of garments be these?
Okay. We'll be back soon.
He consorts with tiny demons
in his hand. 'Tis witchcraft, I say.
Do I look like I'm here
to play pretend with you?
Relax. It's not personal.
Just tell them you're a
time traveler or something.
Well, if we're gonna be
here, we might as well enjoy it.
Our knight just
vomited inside the MRI.
Taub thinks it might
be food poisoning.
Which shouldn't be surprising.
Outdoor latrines, food prep
going on next to livestock.
I hear you wish to speak
with me concerning Sir William.
How faireth he?
Not well, or we
wouldn't be here.
A pox indeed is... Miles.
We just thought it
was a concussion.
He's going to be okay, right?
We need to look at the
area he was camping out in.
And you might want to invest
into a dental plan for the kingdom.
You sure he got sick
from something here?
I'm not sure of
anything, yet, but...
What do you make of this?
Mmm. Looks like vomit.
Means he was showing
symptoms prior to the fight.
True, but I meant this.
Oh. It's a cow eye from the
night before the tournament.
He makes the knights eat
all kinds of disgusting stuff.
Why?
Got the idea from Fear Factor.
Why didn't he mention it when
he checked into the hospital?
I make them all take an oath
of secrecy about the ritual.
William tends to take his
role as a knight very seriously.
You think that's what
caused him to pass out?
It's not exactly sanitary.
Fun stuff never is.
Serious bacterial food poisoning
explains seizure and vomiting.
A lumbar puncture could confirm.
Except it's not food poisoning.
If it was, the ER would
look like Camelot right now.
All it takes is one bad eyeball.
Or testicle, cow brain,
or my personal favorite,
pig rectum with a
side order of sphincter.
I think they call that
breakfast in Australia.
No one else was sick because
they weren't allergic like he was.
To what? That's what I
sent you to Middle Earth
to find out.
Run scratch tests with the
samples you brought back.
That's gonna take time,
and he's getting worse.
So treat him with
epinephrine, too.
This should prevent
any more symptoms
until we can figure out
what it is you're allergic to.
Thanks.
I told you, you shouldn't
have eaten all that stuff.
You know, you
don't have to stay.
I'm sure you and Miles are crazy
busy, what with the wedding and all.
Miles said we could
postpone it until...
Don't worry, I'll be fine. I'll be there. I
just hope you have a good photographer.
'Cause I don't think the standard
red-eye filter's going to work on these.
I need your right arm.
That feels... Feels strange.
What is it? What's wrong?
His heart rate's
become irregular.
My chest hurts. It feels
like it's going to explode.
Tachycardia. We need to
shock him back into rhythm.
Oh, my God, William...
I need his gown open.
What is that?
What is that stuff?
I don't know.
It's definitely not an allergy,
or the epi would have helped
him, not made him worse.
Unless he's allergic and allergic
to the cure. Sodium bisulfite,
the preservative that keeps epi
peppy, can cause tachycardia.
So can Wolff-Parkinson-
White syndrome,
and it also causes
hemorrhaging in the eyes.
And abnormal electrical pathways in
the heart, which could cause seizures.
But not skin infections.
There is an infection that can
cause skin and neurological damage
and spreads rapidly
without treatment.
Methicillin-resistant
staphylococcus aureus?
Lord have MRSA.
You weren't wearing gloves when
we shocked his heart back into rhythm.
I'm sure you'll be fine. You two,
get a sample to the lab to confirm.
You get the knight into
isolation and on IV antibiotics.
You, stay away from me.
Need to talk. About the MRSA?
I know. We're... MRSA, shmrsa.
Something important.
Something you think is more important
than a potentially lethal bacteria
spreading like wildfire
through my hospital?
Well, that narrows it down to
something personal and stupid.
Wilson. Theory confirmed.
He is dating his
first wife, I know.
I don't believe it.
That he didn't ask
your permission first?
No, that he's actually capable
of keeping a secret from me.
Well, you'd be surprised how
many things Wilson doesn't tell you.
Would I? Like how you slept
with your father's best friend? Or...
I'm going to kill him.
You need to break them up.
Forget it.
So you'd rather
sit back and watch
while the evil blonde gorges
on Wilson's tender flesh
and then tosses out his
bones like she did the last time?
You remember what
he was like after that?
Yes, I do.
Well, then do something.
God knows he's not
gonna listen to me.
You, on the other hand, have
decades of experience dating
and being attracted to losers.
Obviously I don't
include myself.
You know what happens when you
interfere in other people's relationships?
Of course, I do it all the time.
Hmm. I see your point.
That is why I'm
staying out of this.
You force him to choose,
you might not like the answer.
He doesn't seem to be
in as much pain any more.
That's good.
But we won't be out of the woods for
sure until the blisters start to recede.
I'm really thirsty. You
mind getting me a soda?
Sure. I'll be right back.
What's wrong?
The pain in my chest,
it's getting worse.
Just now? No.
I didn't want to worry her.
So how long have you
been in love with her?
What? No, we're just friends.
Seriously.
Since the first time I saw her.
Why don't you tell her?
She's engaged to my friend.
The King?
Haven't seen him visiting
or sitting by your bedside.
He has responsibilities.
Yeah? I'm guessing
the Queen does, too.
What kind of knight
steals his friend's bride?
I hate that I even
think about it.
You're not a knight.
You're just a guy.
But I want to be more than that.
Your chest?
No, my back.
Feels like there's
a knife in it.
Is the infection spreading?
It's not MRSA.
It looks like some sort
of clostridial organism.
Question is, which type of
clostridium? There's hundreds.
C. perfringens?
Wouldn't account for his other
symptoms. C. tetani, on the other hand?
Tetanus? He would have
been inoculated against it.
So he cut himself and
didn't get a booster shot.
The guy fights people with swords
for fun, no one said he's smart.
They don't just fight for fun.
They fight to
prove their bravery.
You buying this honor stuff?
Fighting is not
brave, it's just stupid.
You would say that.
You think I've never
been in a fight?
No, I just think
you've never won one.
I took on three
guys in college once.
Hope they bought
you dinner first.
It's not MRSA. I know.
- It's poison ivy.
- Poison ivy?
A severe reaction
could cause the blisters
and maybe irritate his eyes
enough to cause the hemorrhaging,
but the chest pain and seizures?
They have bonfires every night.
Burning leaves
aerosolizes the oil.
You've seen what it's done
to the outside of his body,
imagine what it's doing to
his lungs and his sinuses.
Okay, maybe it remotely fits,
but I'd rather go with scientific
evidence than with your gut.
How about this?
Apparently, it's
all over his sword.
It's his heart rate again!
How fast is it? It's
slowing. Why aren't you...
It's not MRSA.
I'm giving him 12
cc's of epinephrine.
He tested positive.
You'll blow his heart out.
If it slows any more,
it's going to stop.
I told you!
And I told you.
That wasn't caused
by poison ivy.
Or epinephrine.
Means the heart problem we ruled
out, we now have to rule back in.
We found clostridium
bacteria in the skin samples.
Clostridium's in dirt
and basically harmless.
But opportunistic, if his
immune system was depressed.
Leukemia? He
would've had symptoms
way before the
Renaissance festival.
Which is true of anything that would
compromise his immune system.
Which means it has to be
some other environmental toxin.
Yesterday he was a healthy
knight, today he's sleeping beauty.
Nothing else fits.
Trichinosis from
eating infected meat?
We already ruled
out food poisoning.
Both the butcher shop and the food
stands at the fair were totally clean.
Then he ate the poison
apple somewhere else,
or maybe you just missed it.
Start treatment for trichinosis
and confirm with a muscle biopsy.
Hey.
I can't believe I'm
about to say this. Sam...
Told you so.
No, she didn't dump me. She
wants to get to know you better.
Damn it! I never should
have let her see me naked.
It goes against all my
instincts, but I said all right.
Why?
She thinks I was
hiding her from you.
You were.
I don't want her to know.
You're asking me to condone a
relationship based on lies and mistrust?
Yeah.
When and where?
Tonight. Venezia. 8:00.
What am I gonna wear?
All my cereal boxes
are at the cleaners.
House, listen.
I know you're worried about me.
And I also know that
that kind of unselfishness
doesn't come naturally to you.
But I don't want your
help. I don't need your help.
Just come to dinner and
be your usual selfish self.
How could I say no?
Miles said he'd stop by later.
Tell him not to.
I don't want to
be seen like this.
You're sick. That's
nothing to be ashamed of.
Unless you're saying
you want me to leave?
No, don't.
I think he's saying it's
different with you, Shannon.
It's a guy thing. They don't like
showing weakness in front of each other.
Right, William?
Right. Maybe when
I'm feeling a little better.
I'm going to take a small
sample of your muscle tissue here.
Do you mind waiting
outside for this?
Don't hurt him.
He's safe with me.
I thought you were
going to tell her.
Not my call, but if you ask
me, she's waiting for you to.
Knights are supposed
to be selfless.
Right, they conquered countries
and built castles by being selfless.
Bravery and loyalty are
great qualities for soldiers.
If you want to be king, sometimes you
have to be willing to take what's yours.
She's not mine.
She's not his either. Not yet.
It's just dinner. Relax.
Trust me, there is no "just"
when House is involved.
We're in the middle
of a restaurant.
What could he possibly do?
That.
Sorry we're late,
but you know girls.
Always fiddling with
the hair and the makeup.
James, Sam, this is Sarah.
It's nice to meet you.
Horace has told me...
House.
House has told me all about you.
Nice to meet you.
What's the diagnosis?
His muscle biopsy's
clean. It's not trichinosis.
House was wrong. This
is not environmental.
Or we screwed up and missed
something at the Renaissance fair.
You think we did?
No, but I think House
will think we did.
What could we have missed?
Fungal infection?
There's nothing in his blood
work even remotely suggesting that.
But it fits the symptoms.
You want to retest every
sample we took for spores?
We'll be here all night.
Have you noticed how
much pain he's been in lately?
And that's relevant how?
Extra pain means extra
cranky, means off his game.
He's not gonna accept
this isn't environmental
unless we give him no choice.
I cannot believe you're
from Bloomington.
I know. Isn't it amazing?
Yeah. Delightful.
Ignore him. He's just
upset that we're having fun.
Do you remember
that little bakery,
the one with the
amazing cupcakes?
Gino's. Oh, yes!
First stop every time I go home.
Me, too.
Remember that strip club?
Girl, I used to work
at that strip club.
Where does it hurt, William?
My legs. It feels
like they're on fire.
Rhabdomyolysis means
his kidneys are failing.
Also means it's not
environmental. We need to move on.
I recommend we start with a full
cancer work-up, starting with the...
Which one of you
checked out the apartment?
House...
His symptoms fit
an environmental...
The test results
don't. We redid...
Search the apartment.
He hasn't been
there in three weeks.
Go! Now!
I liked him better when
he was on Vicodin.
You and Thirteen
check out his place.
While you're wasting your
time, we'll ultrasound the liver.
If it's cancer, it's as good
a place as any to start.
Hey. Hey.
Heard House met Sam.
The first time he was naked.
The second time, he brought a
transvestite prostitute to dinner.
Overall, it could've been worse.
Great.
That's your reaction?
What?
Nudity, prostitutes...
Sorry. Preoccupied.
House said something
to you, didn't he?
No. He didn't.
It is a little crazy,
though. I mean, isn't it?
I mean, things seem
to be going great,
but they seemed to be
going great 12 years ago.
The good things are still good.
She's still smart,
funny, gets me.
And she's less competitive.
Either she's changed or
I've changed, but either way...
Am I out of my mind?
You never know what can happen.
Might as well give it a chance.
Yeah.
Looks like you were right.
Tumors, dozens of them
inside and on the surface.
Pull in closer.
See that?
What is that?
I don't know, but it's
definitely not cancer.
Kitchen's clean.
Bedroom as well.
Most dangerous thing in his
medicine cabinet was dental floss.
It's locked. Key
wasn't on his ring.
You honestly want to go back
and tell House we didn't check
every square inch of this place?
Of course not.
My hero.
What the hell is this?
Either a secret
entrance to Hogwarts
or our knight is a witch.
Our knight is into some
seriously creepy stuff.
He claims it's just sugar water,
but we sent the rest
down to the lab for testing.
You think he poisoned himself?
It's not poison. We would have
picked it up in his blood work.
Not if it collected
slowly in his liver
and it all started leaking
into his system at once.
These tumors that aren't tumors,
what if they're focal hepatic
lesions filled with blood?
Every time one explodes,
it'd be releasing another dose.
Of what?
Plumbum nigrum.
You putting a hex on someone?
It's Latin for black lead.
Our knight/warlock apparently
also dabbles in alchemy.
Lead poisoning?
Seizures, paralysis, weak immune
system and eventually coma.
Biopsy the cysts,
you'll find your lead.
You think we'll make the 7:30?
I'm sorry. If I don't change, I'm
gonna feel like I'm at work all night.
Yeah, I remember.
Is it a problem?
Not at all.
In fact, if we hurry...
We will definitely
not make the 7:30.
Well, there's always the 9:40.
Or not.
Shouldn't you be
at the hospital?
Wouldn't need a team if I
did all the work, now, would I?
Plus, I had to make you dinner.
We have plans.
Bet your plans
don't taste like this.
Don't!
House, whatever it
is that you're up to...
I'm trying to be nice.
What I did the other night
was juvenile. I'm sorry.
Yeah.
Soufflé was amazing.
It's my mom's recipe.
Everything else, I got off the web.
Here's to the Internet.
Where I found the lamb ragù
and you two found
each other. Again.
Well, it wasn't
just the Internet.
Yeah, more like
divorce, depression,
therapy, more therapy,
then the Internet.
Yeah.
And here we are.
Exactly. And here we are.
Well, I need to go
to the bathroom.
I think you're old enough now, but if
you'd like me to come along with you...
I mean, is it safe to
leave the two of you?
Come on, James, enough already.
Yeah, James. I cook in peace.
Okay. Be right back.
You're a cold-hearted bitch
who ripped his heart out.
I watched him struggle for years
to overcome the damage you did,
and there's no way I'm just
gonna let you reel him back in
so you can do it all over again.
And all this?
Phase two of getting
to know my enemy.
You're wrong about me.
But I'm glad now I don't
have to pretend I like you,
except for when James
is standing next to me.
Same here. The only
difference is, I'll outlast you.
And scene.
Well, it's too late
for the movie.
Wanna see what's on TV?
Absolutely.
Love to.
There wasn't any lead present
in his blood work or liver biopsy.
And his heart rate and BP
are getting even more erratic.
We had to shock it back into
rhythm twice during the night.
There's only one
thing left to do.
We're wasting our time.
Actually, I've already
gotten good value.
I told you there's nothing here that
could've caused any of his symptoms.
No, you told me that you
couldn't find anything here
that could be
causing his symptoms.
And now we're gonna find something
new because we're in costume?
We looked everywhere.
Tested everything.
Just because Wilson's acting
stupid doesn't mean we are.
You think he's making a mistake?
Of course. But he'll
figure it out sooner or later.
Hopefully after a few
weeks of great sex.
Nothing ventured,
nothing gained.
Wilson's not like us.
He cares too much about
people and their feelings.
Thanks for the compliment.
The code that our
knight claims to live by,
all that crap about honor and
chivalry, Wilson's naturally like that.
Which is why he is...
A great guy.
A sucker and a target.
Someone's got to look out for him.
You smell that?
Yeah, it's the apothecary shop,
and, yes, Foreman
and I already...
I cry your pardon, sir.
You know what this is?
Why, that's lavender.
Try rose hips.
Both harmless. Who cares?
It could be cyanide,
as far as he knows.
How about this?
Be nothing but St John's wort.
Wrong again. Black Cohosh.
My uncle owns the shop.
I just started apprenticing.
What's the big deal?
Hey, I just organized all that.
You know what this is?
A wild carrot?
It's hemlock, you
embossed carbuncle.
That's hemlock? You sure?
Did you sell it to anyone?
It's poison. Think hard.
It was just one branch.
You sold it to Sir William.
No. To the King.
It's the only part of the
environment you didn't check.
The people living in it.
What's going on? Why
can't we see William?
Because you poisoned
him, your royal anus, with this.
Wild carrots?
Hemlock.
I need to know how much you
used and how you prepared it.
You did something to William?
No, of course not.
He's still alive. You want to avoid
a murder charge, start talking fast.
The apothecary's willing to testify
that you're the only one he gave it to.
Okay. Yeah, maybe I bought
it for the food challenge,
but I didn't know
that was hemlock.
If it was for the challenge,
why is Wee Willy the
only knight who's dying?
I don't know.
I'm telling you, I didn't know.
Why would I want to hurt William?
I can think of at
least one reason.
Miles, please, whatever
happened, just tell them the truth.
I am.
I swear.
We ran a gas
chromatography on his blood,
found trace amounts
of piperidine alkaloids.
The main markers of
hemlock intoxication.
Well, the good news is, we
now know what's wrong with you.
Bad news is, your king's precious
ideals were just pretend after all.
At least when it comes to guys
who get too close to his Queen.
It's not true.
I guess you've never
heard the expression,
"Gas chromatography
machines don't lie."
Neither does Miles.
He's the best knight
I've ever known.
That's why he was chosen king.
Miles is a jealous idiot,
and you're just an idiot.
Something's wrong.
We performed a gastric lavage
and administered activated charcoal,
but he's getting
worse, not better.
It's been in his
system two days.
We're lucky he's
lasted this long.
If it was hemlock, he'd
either be dead already
or getting better
with treatment.
It's hemlock. We
found it in his blood.
He may have had some hemlock,
but it's not what's killing him.
Don't do it, whatever
you're planning,
especially if you're
gonna use that thing.
It was just sitting
in a stone...
Here. It's gonna cost extra 'cause
of the level of detail that you wanted.
Anything good? And by
good, I, of course, mean bad.
Nope. Pretty much
your typical life.
Married young, got divorced.
Married a little less
young, got divorced.
She's been pretty successful in
everything she's done except marriage.
Well, there's gotta be
something I can use.
Maybe. Didn't read her
shrink's notes. Didn't seem right.
But stealing them did?
Whoa! I didn't steal them. I
found a way to obtain them.
Excuse me. I don't mean to
interrupt, but you got a minute?
Sure.
Oh, him? Yeah. I
was just leaving.
Careful, I have a sword.
I don't agree with
what you said,
but I understand
why you said it.
We were married young.
We both made mistakes.
And, yes, I did
make most of them.
But that was almost
a decade ago.
I'm sorry, is that the statutory
period for soul sucking?
I'm not asking you
to like me, House.
To be honest, I
think you're an ass,
but we do have one
thing in common.
We care about James.
So prove it and dump him. Again.
You're pretty much insufferable
all the time, aren't you?
Sorry. Go on. And yes.
We just reconnected, we have
no idea where we're headed.
But is it really too much to ask
that you give us a chance to find out?
I'm sure I'll be
seeing you around.
We did it. Well, I did it.
What exactly did we do?
You do?
These aren't focal
hepatic lesions on his liver.
They're peliosis
hepatis lesions,
which, in combination with an
erratic heart rate, usually indicates...
Endocarditis, an
infection on his heart valve.
Two major symptoms
of anabolic steroid abuse.
No, he wouldn't...
And the rhabdo makes the third.
Our patient's a juicer.
The ancient poison accelerated
the damage of the modern poison.
Start treatment. Let
the king out of the tower.
How are you feeling?
Ashamed.
You should be.
You'll compromise
your ideals to win a fight,
but not to go for
the woman you love.
That was a game, not real life.
I didn't...
Hurt anyone? Try
telling that to Shannon.
Or maybe I missed something
while she was crying by your bed.
You don't need to
win anyone's heart.
You just need to ask for it.
Miles is a great guy.
He's rich, smart,
treats her well.
She's going to have
a great life with him.
With me?
I'd do everything
I could for her,
but even at my best,
it wouldn't be much.
And she deserves the best.
I guess I'd rather she be
happy, even if it means I'm not.
Guess House was
right about that, too.
What?
You really are an idiot.