You weren't born to be king, Loki.
You were born to cause pain
and suffering and death.
The Time-Keepers are all
that stand between us
and full-scale calamity.
- For all time.
- Always.
Why am I locked in here?
You were disloyal to the TVA.
You were in the Time-Keepers'
chambers. They weren't real.
- And why does that change anything?
- That changes everything!
The nexus event
the two of you caused,
whatever that connection is,
can bring this whole place down.
This is new for me. Back on Lamentis...
I can help you if you trust me.
The person we're after
is beyond The Void at the end of time.
That thing is just their guard dog
protecting the only way in.
- How do we get past the guard dog?
- I'm gonna enchant it.
She's pretty confident.
Go!
Way to go, Tic Tac!
That's how you punch.
Wakanda forever!
You haven't heard of me.
- Let me put you on hold.
- Dance-off, bro.
- A friend from work.
- I can do this all day.
- Yeah, I know.
- I'll show you ferocity.
Higher, further, faster, baby.
We have a Hulk.
We're gonna jump on that spaceship
and get out of here. Wanna come?
We think of time
as a one-way motion.
One small step for man...
How dare they!
My dream...
We have fought
for the right to experience peace.
Glorious purpose!
Motivated by women
throughout the world.
What is grief,
if not love persevering?
I will rise.
Open your eyes.
Aren't you gonna tell me
not to kick the door in?
It never made a difference.
Well, if you think it's a bad idea,
I prefer you to speak your mind.
No. Nothing to say.
That'll be a first.
Everything okay?
Yeah. Just need a moment.
Right.
- It's just, you normally...
- Loki, shut up.
I was pruned before you even existed.
I have been waiting for this moment
my entire life.
I just need a second
to get my head straight, okay?
Sure. Of course.
Hey, y'all.
You again?
Welcome to The Citadel at the End of Time.
Come on.
Congratulations.
Y'all had an awfully long journey
to get here.
He's impressed.
Who's impressed?
He Who Remains.
And who is he?
He created all and he controls all.
At the end, it is only He Who Remains.
And he wants to offer you a deal.
He's been making
a few creative adjustments,
and he's worked it out so we can reinsert
both of y'all back into the Timeline
in a way that won't disrupt things.
- "Won't disrupt things"?
- Mmm-hmm.
The TVA can keep doin' its vital work
and y'all can live the lives
you've always wanted.
And what have we always wanted?
Now,
don't play coy with me, mister.
You know how you got into this mess.
What?
The Battle of New York, silly.
You versus those self-righteous Avengers.
How would you like to win?
But not just there.
You can kill Thanos.
You want the Infinity Gauntlet? Yours.
Throne of Asgard? No problem.
What about you, missy?
All those years on the run.
Desperate, alone.
How would you like to wake up tomorrow
with just a lifetime of happy memories?
Two Lokis in the same place.
Both of us...
together on the Timeline.
It's crazy, but he could make it work.
All of it.
Everything.
Exactly the way you've always wanted.
And you can have it all, together.
It's fiction.
We write our own destiny now.
Oh, sure you do. Good luck with that.
Come on.
Hey, there.
- What took you so long?
- Sorry.
Some things had to get worked out,
but I'm downloadin'
the files you need now.
This isn't what I asked for.
I know, but he thinks
this'll be more useful.
Who?
Happy readin'.
He Who Remains.
Not for much longer.
Are we sure he's even still alive?
This is wild.
The two of you...
...same person.
I mean, it's a little unnatural. But...
Wow!
Wild.
He Who Remains.
She still calls me that?
Creepy, right? But...
I like it.
Come on. Come on, let's talk in my office.
Not what you were expecting, hmm?
You're just... a man.
Mmm.
Flesh and blood.
- Don't tell me I'm a disappointment.
- No.
Just a little bit easier to kill.
Come on in.
One...
Two.
Please, take a seat.
Uh, Loki.
Loki.
Two sugars.
I said I wasn't to be disturbed.
Well, then you're not gonna
be happy to see me.
He's back.
If anyone was ever gonna
make it back from The Void,
I suppose it was gonna be you.
Oh, well, you know, one man's Void
is another man's piece of cake.
- So, you're gonna prune me?
- I like that idea.
But, you know, my standards might be a
little bit higher in that area than yours.
- You know, with close personal friends.
- I'm sorry, Mobius.
I couldn't let you get in the way
of our mission.
Mission?
The Time-Keepers are fake.
We're all Variants. What mission?
It can't have been for nothing.
That's why I had to prune you.
Hunter D-90 to my office, immediately.
Yeah. Sorry, Ravonna. That's not gonna
work out the way you think it is,
now that we know your secret.
What did you do?
Stay alert, she's close.
Secure the perimeter. I've got her.
Stand down, B-15.
You need to listen to me.
- There'll be time for that.
- Just wait.
What the hell is going on here?
Judge Renslayer.
What?
Who are you? And what the hell
are you doing in my school?
That isn't Judge Renslayer.
How?
We have a lot to talk about.
Been a long journey for you, hasn't it?
Lot of running, lot of pain.
And you...
You're a flea on the back
of a dragon.
In for one hell of a ride.
But you did manage to hang on.
Mmm-hmm. I guess
that counts for something.
I'm not sure you quite understand
the situation.
You've lost.
We found you.
Duh. Of course you did.
Whoa!
A swing and a miss.
So, we're still doing that, hmm?
Let's get all this out of the way.
Okay.
Here we go.
You can't kill me because
I already know what's going to happen.
See?
It's a parlor trick.
Okay.
Don't you wonder how I'm able to get out
of the way just before you kill me?
No. It's because of that little TemPad
you have there.
Right.
But how do I already have it loaded up
with everything I need to know
to keep from being killed by you two?
It's easy.
I know it all.
And I've seen it all.
Everything you guys
did on Lamentis, I saw.
All the stuff the TVA
didn't know about, I knew.
All the scheming, all the...
...talking.
That little look by the lake.
Quite sentimental, very touching stuff,
by the way.
No.
No, we broke out of your little game.
That's how we got here.
No, wrong.
Every step you took to get here,
Lamentis, The Void,
I paved the road.
You...
You just walked down it.
And I have the rest,
uh, right here.
Everything that's, uh...
that's going to happen.
There's only one way this can go.
Then why are we here?
Oh, come on.
You know you can't get to the end
until you've been changed by the journey.
This stuff, it needs to happen.
To get us all in the right mindset
to finish the quest.
- Right.
So, it's all a game.
It's all... a manipulation.
Interesting, that your head
would go to that.
Sylvie,
you think you can trust this guy?
- Don't listen to him.
- "Don't listen to him."
Do you think you're even capable
of trusting anyone at all?
I think people are ready
to hear a little truth now.
You know, like the TVA is a lie.
But what if it's a necessary one?
Someone created the Time-Keepers.
They created this whole place.
They gave us all purpose.
I have to believe they had a reason.
No, because I've seen the horror
waiting for people when they get pruned
and there's nothing necessary
about that.
You know what would happen
if we didn't prune the Timeline?
- What?
- Chaos. Death.
Free will?
Only one person gets free will.
The one in charge.
"Friends across time, allies to the end."
- Shut up.
- That was so beautiful.
And then you sent me to die.
What happened to you?
Nothing, Mobius. I didn't change.
You didn't change? You betrayed me.
No, no. You betrayed me!
I looked out for you,
hung my neck out for you,
and you suffer a crisis of faith
and turn to those Variants?
Eons of friendship.
And you threw it all away
on a couple of Lokis.
No, Mobius. I didn't betray you.
We can't take away people's free will,
Ravonna. Do you not see that?
- What are you doing?
- What I need to do.
Wait, stop.
Look, maybe we can build this
into something better together.
I'm sorry, Mobius.
I'm not gonna let you go.
Please, Mobius.
Even with that...
you're of no danger to me.
Is that what you think?
Let's see.
Yep, you were right.
Back here again.
Go ahead.
Where are you gonna go?
In search of free will.
I understand your moral objections
to what the TVA does.
And my methods are deceptive.
But the mission, it never was.
Without the me, without the TVA...
everything burns.
Then what are you so afraid of?
Me.
And just who are you?
Oh, I've been dubbed many names
by many people.
A ruler, a conqueror.
He Who Remains, a jerk.
But it's... it's not as simple as a name.
Eons ago, before the TVA,
a variant of myself lived on Earth
in the 31st century.
He was a scientist
and he discovered that there were
universes stacked on top of his own.
At the same time, other versions of us
were learning the same thing.
Naturally, they made contact.
And for a while, there was peace.
Narcissistic, self-congratulatory peace.
"I love your shoes." "I love your hair."
"Oh, man, nice nose." "Thanks, man."
Et cetera.
They shared technology and knowledge.
Using the best of their universes
to improve the others.
However...
not every version of me
was so... so pure of heart.
To some of us,
new worlds meant only one thing,
new lands to be conquered.
The peace between realities...
...erupted into all-out war,
each variant fighting to preserve
their universe
and annihilate the others.
This was almost the end...
...ladies and gentlemen,
of everything and everyone.
And then the Time-Keepers
came along and saved us all.
Amen
No. No.
Nope, this is where we diverge
from the dogma.
That first variant encountered a creature
created from all the tears in reality,
capable of consuming time
and space itself.
A creature...
you both know.
Alioth.
Bingo!
I harnessed the beast's power
and began experimenting on it.
I weaponized Alioth
and I ended...
I ended the Multiversal War.
Once I isolated our timeline,
all I had to do
was manage the flow of time
and prevent any further branches.
Hence, the TVA.
Hence, the Time-Keepers
and a highly efficient bureaucracy.
Hence, ages...
...and ages of cosmic harmony.
Hence...
you're welcome.
You came to kill the devil, right?
Well, guess what?
I keep you safe.
And if you think I'm evil, well,
just wait till you meet my variants.
And that's the gambit.
Stifling order or cataclysmic chaos.
You may hate the dictator,
but something...
...far worse is gonna fill that void
if you depose of him.
I've lived a million lifetimes.
I've gone through every scenario.
This is the only way.
The TVA,
it works.
Or you're a liar.
Or I'm a liar.
So you just...
continue to prune innocent timelines?
Mmm-mmm.
You two would.
There's two options! One...
you kill me and destroy all this,
so you don't just have one devil,
you have an infinite amount. Or...
you two.
You two run the thing.
You're lying.
Why would you give up being in control?
Buddy...
I'm tired.
And I'm older.
I'm older than I look.
This game is for the young, the hungry.
I've gone through a lot of scenarios...
trying to find the right person
to take this spot.
It turns out that person came in two.
But it's definitely you two.
So, no more lies.
You kill me and the Sacred Timeline
is completely exposed.
Multiversal War.
Or you take over and return to the TVA
as its benevolent rulers.
Tell the workforce who they are
and why they do what they do.
You treated real people's lives
like some kind of game.
It's not personal, it's practical.
It was personal to me.
Grow up! Grow up, Sylvie!
Murderer! Hypocrite!
We're all villains here.
We've all done horrible,
terrible, horrific things.
But now, we, you...
have a chance to do them
for a good reason.
We just crossed...
the threshold.
Oh.
So, I fibbed.
I fibbed earlier when I said
I know how everything's going to go. I...
I know... I knew...
...everything up to a certain point,
and that point was about...
seven, eight, nine, ten seconds ago.
But now I have no idea.
No idea how the rest of this
is going to go.
I'm being candid.
So, that's it?
That's it?
This is what happens at the end of time?
And now you're just gonna sit there
with all that freedom and...
let us decide your fate?
Yes!
Yes! Yes! What's the worst
that can happen?
You either...
take over and my life's work continues
or you plunge a blade in my chest
and an infinite amount of me...
start another Multiversal War.
And I just...
end up right back here anyways.
Reincarnation, baby.
No, it's just another lie.
Another manipulation.
Oh.
No lie.
No manipulation.
Wow.
I love this.
I love... all this honesty.
Feels like a fresh start.
Oh, holy...
- What're you doing?
- Hang on a moment.
Let's just talk about it.
Well, how about we finish what we started
and kill him?
- What if he's telling the truth?
- So what?
- I believe him.
- Believe what?
That a bazillion boogeymen
will turn up
just because we give people free will?
- He's a liar, Loki.
- So am I.
And I don't think he was lying.
Not about that.
Insane? Yes.
But maybe he was telling the truth.
Better hurry.
Timeline's already branching.
- So, what are you suggesting?
- That we think about it.
And what precisely
is there to think about?
Weren't you listening
to what he was saying?
That's the gambit.
Remove the dictator
and what fills the void?
Ah.
You want the throne?
No, that's not it. No.
- I don't believe you.
- Sylvie, the universe is in the balance,
everything we know to be true. Everything.
I know the TVA has hurt us both.
But what if by taking him out,
we risk unleashing something even worse?
All I'm suggesting is we just
take a minute to think about it.
I promise you from my heart
this isn't about a throne.
What was I thinking trusting you?
Has this whole thing been a con?
Really?
That's what you think of me...
after all this time?
Sure. Why not?
Evil Loki's master plan comes together.
Well, you never trusted me, did you?
What was the point?
Can't you see?
This is bigger than our experience.
Why aren't we seeing this the same way?
Because you can't trust...
and I can't be trusted.
Then I guess we're in a pickle.
Sylvie, wait.
Wait.
Sylvie. Sylvie.
Maybe he's lying! Maybe he's not.
The cost of getting this wrong
is too great.
Fine. Do it.
Kill me. Take your throne.
No.
Sylvie, stop. Stop.
Stop.
I've been where you are.
I've felt what you feel.
Don't ask me how I know.
All I know...
is I don't wanna hurt you.
I don't want a throne.
I just...
I just want you to be okay.
But I'm not you.
Incredible.
Aren't you gonna beg for your life?
Um, could, could.
I'll see you soon.
No turning back now.
Who said anything about turning back?
"For all time."
"Always."
Copy. Reporting to the armory, sir.
That's, what, 63 new branches
in this unit alone?
Does he want us
to just let them all branch?
- At this point, how are we gonna stop it?
- We can't!
What?
What'd you say?
It's done, Mobius.
We made a terrible mistake.
- What's done?
- What?
We freed the Timeline.
We found him beyond the storm.
A Citadel at the End of Time.
He's terrifying. He planned everything.
He's seen everything. He knows everything.
It's complicated. Okay?
- Right.
- But someone is coming.
Countless different versions
of a very dangerous person.
And they're all set on war.
We need to prepare.
Take it easy.
You're an analyst, right?
- What division are you from?
- What?
- What are you talking about?
- Who are you? What's your name?
Boots on the ground now. Archives.
Who are you?