Previously on "LOST."
You got to trust me
when I tell you this.
I am trying to help you.
Do I know you?
I'm George Minkowski.
I'm the communications officer.
Where is the radio room?
I'll take you there.
And how do we get out of here?
Through the door.
It looks like you guys
have a friend on this boat.
You're pregnant.
Juliet, she was their
fertility doctor,
studying pregnant women.
The reason the Others wanted
her baby was for research.
What happens to pregnant
women on this island?
They die.
You want me to help
you and your baby,
I have answers to
your questions.
But you have to come
with me, right now.
The baby isn't Jin's.
I'm going to look at
your baby and determine
the date of conception.
But if you got pregnant here?
We'll cross that bridge
when we come to it.
The baby was conceived
about eight weeks ago.
You got pregnant on the island.
So how long do I have?
Most of the women
made it into the middle
of their second trimester.
Nobody made it to their third.
Lapidus.
You ready?
I'll be up.
Don't be late, Frank.
Regina.
Frank.
I didn't hear you.
Sorry, I didn't
mean to spook you.
The captain wanted me to
bring these guys some grub.
OK.
You know, your
book's upside down.
I'm just trying to help.
I thought I'd check in on you
guys, bring you some food.
How you feeling, by the way?
Yeah, much better, thanks.
Why are we being held captive?
We had nothing to do
with Minkowski's death.
This has nothing to
do with Minkowski.
The captain wasn't very
happy that you two decided
to bust out of sickbay
and into our radio room.
We didn't bust out.
The door was left open.
We assumed it was you.
Why the hell would I do that?
Did you have any contact
with our people on the beach?
No luck.
Something must have
happened to their phone.
Lima beans?
Sorry.
We had a little
problem in the kitchen.
Just stay put, all right.
I still want to
talk to the captain.
No, you don't.
Regina.
Let's talk about baby names.
Good.
We're getting better.
Mm, hm.
But no, Jin.
Deal.
Ahh.
Phoo, haa.
Ohh.
No.
What happened?
You mean before or after
the redhead knocked me out?
She hit you?
When I ran into them on the
way back from Locke's camp.
Why would she do that?
Ah, I guess she didn't want
to have to explain why she was
on her way to a
poison gas factory.
Juliet told Jack that
it's a power station.
Why would Juliet
lie about that?
Force of habit.
Why were they going there?
To turn it off,
deactivate the gas.
At least they wanted to
earn some brownie points.
Do you think they're
really going to rescue us?
In all the time
they've been here,
they talked about
a lot of things,
and none involved rescuing us.
Good morning.
Good morning. morning
I hope they resolve
their kitchen issues.
Sayid.
What's that?
It's a note.
Three days ago, when
I was in Locke's camp,
Ben claimed he had
a spy on this boat.
Hello.
My name is Sun.
Hi, Sun.
Hi.
I'm Daniel Something
I can help you with?
I'm two months pregnant.
Oh, you're... wow.
That's... congratulations.
So you're here to rescue us?
It's a simple question.
Are you or are you not
going to rescue us?
The thing is, um, it's
not really my call, Sun.
Then whose call is it?
Thank you.
Uh, can you pass,
uh, the cereal?
Pretty good English, Jin.
Thank you.
I understand better
than I, uh, speak.
Hm.
Has Sun been teaching you or
are you just picking it up?
Uh, Sun teach me.
Uh, Sawyer, too.
Sun is better.
I bet.
Hey, Sun.
How you feeling?
I'm good.
Thank you.
The morning sickness has
stopped, which has been nice.
That's good.
Well, if you need anything,
just let me know, OK.
Would you like some breakfast?
What are you doing?
I needed another
bottle of those
vitamins you gave me,
the, the pre-natals?
You could have just asked.
You're right, I should have.
What happened to the
last ones I gave you?
Sorry?
The last bottle I gave, there
should should be 20 left.
Are you planning a trip?
Please, just give
me the vitamins.
Where are you going, Sun?
We're going to Locke's camp.
What?
Why?
Because I don't
trust these people.
Whether you trust them or
not, you can't go there.
Locke doesn't want
to leave the island.
And I told you, Sun, pregnant
women, they don't survive here.
Yes.
You did tell me that.
You don't believe me.
Look, I know that I have
been less than truthful
about certain things
since coming here.
But I promise you,
Sun, I promise you,
I'm not lying about this.
After everything
you've confided in me,
I should at least
have your trust.
Claire's baby is fine.
I feel fine.
All I have are your stories
that I'm going to get sick.
I'm going to do what's best
for me and for my baby,
because, no, I don't trust you.
Oh, taxi!
Ahh!
Once you hit the stream, you
want to head northwest, pretty
much in a straight line
for about a day and a half.
Thank you.
I'm going to have to tell Jack.
But I'll give you guys
a nice, long head-start.
I'd tell him myself, but
he wouldn't understand.
No, he wouldn't.
You'd better get going.
Be safe, OK?
Thank you.
She's not going anywhere.
Sun, this is a bad idea.
What concern is it of yours?
Do you understand your wife's
medical condition right now?
Translate for me.
No.
Your wife is very sick.
If she doesn't get off
this island in three weeks,
she will die.
If you let her go,
your wife is in danger.
Jin, danger.
Wherever Sun go, I go.
Sun, please.
Jin, your wife had an affair.
What?
Sun was with another man.
She thought the baby was his.
Oh, you going fishing?
Uh, you mind if I tag along.
Oh.
Oh, I am sorry.
I, I didn't me to interrupt.
No.
Come.
You sure?
Yes.
Come.
You realise we're the only
tow married guys on the island?
Married?
Married.
Yeah, well, no,
not to each other.
No.
You got it.
It's not easy, is it?
Oh, I mean, it's,
it's wonderful.
But, let's face it, every
decision that you make
takes twice as long.
'Cause you always got
to talk them into it.
Rose has cancer.
She's sick.
Dying.
Well, at least she was dying.
She says she's better now.
She says it's this
place, the island.
But when the camp
split up, I was sure
that she'd want
to go with Locke.
Why would she want
to leave the island
and risk getting sick again?
Then why do you stay with Jack?
Because it was the
right thing to do.
Locke, he's a murderer.
See, it's all about karma, Jin.
Do you know karma?
You make bad choices,
bad things happen to you.
Or you make good choices, and
then good... hey, hey, hey, hey.
You got one.
Yeah, here, pull it in.
Wow, look at that.
Now, you see?
Now that's karma.
We must be the good guys, huh?
How long's that going
to go on for, eh?
Why don't they just fix
whatever the bloody hell
is causing that?
That sound is not mechanical.
What, you think
somebody's doing that?
Somebody is just banging
those pipes again and again?
That's exactly what I think.
Gentlemen, thanks
for your patience.
The captain would
like to see you now.
Where's the helicopter?
Lapidus is running an errand.
What kind of errand?
I'm a doctor.
I don't know where he's going.
Did he go to the island?
Do you know
anywhere else he can land?
What's he
going to do there?
I said
I'm just a doctor.
What did Lapidus say?
He didn't say anything.
What is he doing there?
Hey.
Hey!
Stop!
That woman just jumped
over the side of the ship.
Don't just stand there!
What's the matter
with you people?
What's wrong with you?
Get the rope!
Why aren't you doing anything?
Bring a rope!
Get the rope!
Get a rope!
Stop.
She just jumped.
It's over.
She's gone.
Everybody get back
to your posts.
That was an order.
I'm Captain Gault.
I suppose you two
have a few questions.
So what can I do for you?
What?
You boys said you
wanted to speak with me.
Let's just start with why
a woman jumped over the side
your ship and you did
nothing to stop it?
I didn't jump in
or order my crew
to jump in, because I didn't
want to lose anymore people.
What exactly is going on here?
Some of my crew have been
dealing with what might best
be described as a heightened
case of cabin fever.
I think it's got something to
do with the close proximity
of the island.
Why don't you turn around then?
I've tried.
But we have a saboteur on board,
and he's done one hell of a job
on my engines.
I've got my crew working around
the clock to repair them.
And then you'll
take our people home?
Then we move to safer waters.
Those are my orders.
And I don't suppose you'd tell
us who gave you those orders?
Sure, I will.
Charles Widmore.
This is Charles Widmore's boat?
That's right, you know him.
Do either of you
know what this is?
It's a flight data recorder,
otherwise known as a black box.
That's exactly what it is.
Now here's the funny
thing, this black box
comes from Oceanic Flight 815.
A salvage vessel recovered it
from the bottom of the ocean.
It took a considerable
amount of Mr.
Widmore's resources
to procure it.
It was found, with the
wreckage of the plane,
along with all 324
dead passengers.
That's not the complete
story, as you are well aware,
Mr. Jarrah, given the fact
that you're standing here,
breathing.
The wreckage was
obviously staged.
Now, can you imagine what
kind of resources and manpower
go into pulling off a
feat of that magnitude?
Faking the recovery
of a plane crash?
Putting 324 families
through a grieving process
based on a lie?
But what's even more
disturbing, where exactly
does one come across
324 dead bodies?
And that, Mr. Jarrah,
Mr. Hume, is just one
of the many reasons we
want Benjamin Linus.
I'm sorry.
I had to stop you
any way I could.
It wasn't your
place to stop us.
I know you don't trust me.
But you need to get
off this island.
We all do.
You want to leave?
More than anything.
I don't know if that boat out
there is the answer or not,
but it's something.
I need to go home.
So do you.
Sun, in about
three weeks, you'll
be in almost constant
state of nausea.
A week after that,
you'll experience
shortness of breath
that won't go away.
A week after that, you'll
consciousness and slip
into a coma and then,
Sun, you will die.
And when your heart stops
beating so will the baby's.
And that, Sun, is why
it is my business.
Because you are my patient.
If you go, you will die.
And your baby will
never be born.
Eahh
Ahhh.
So what did you
think of the captain?
He was surprisingly
forthcoming.
Yeah, he tells it like it is.
Just don't piss him off.
You know what I mean?
I think you'll like your room.
It's on the quiet
part of the ship.
This ship is moving.
Well, if you say so.
That shouldn't still be there.
Damn it.
Hey, Johnson, is that you?
Johnson?
Yeah.
Mop this up.
Sorry, I got to go up on deck.
No, you're going
to mop this up.
Kevin, this is, uh,
Sayid.
Desmond.
Kevin Johnson.
Nice to meet you, Kevin.
I made dinner.
Is the baby mine?
Heh.
Hm heh.
I can't believe you
came all this way.
Are you kidding?
Is anyone else coming?
No.
Good So where is she?
Hm hm.
Come here.
She's awesome.
Thank you.
Would you like to hold her?
I don't know.
I, I kind of have
two left hands.
I trust you.
Wow.
She looks just like Jin.
Yes, she does.
So, I guess we should,
like, go see him.
Of course.
Bad Robot.