=Lost You Forever S2=
=Episode 2=
The Central Plains
are indeed prosperous.
No wonder His Majesty wishes
to establish the capital here.
Being sentimental
is a fatal for a man.
That boy Cang Xuan
is not as ambitious and intimidating
as the old King of Xiyan.
Back then...
Xiyan braised mutton.
Gu Shu grilled silkworms.
There's a story
about this braised mutton.
When the Great Emperor
won a big victory
in a battle,
he rewarded the three armies.
As it was cold,
he stewed the mutton
in a big pot
and shared it with the soldiers.
And the dish Gu Shu grilled silkworms
was created by Queen Xiezu.
It looks frightening,
but it's rich
in nutrients.
I didn't expect
to eat authentic Xiyan dishes
in Central Plains.
Get the cook here,
and I'll reward him well.
Yes.
It's been a long time
since I've eaten
such authentic Xiyan food.
If it were not for Cang Xuan,
we would be drinking and eating at home.
Come on. Let's drink.
Eat.
This tastes good.
So authentic.
It's the taste of Xiyan.
Everyone.
This is the cook
who prepared the dishes for you.
Please.
- Greetings, Your Majesty.
Rise.
Please get up.
Please rise.
- Thank you, Your Majesty.
No offense.
I really don't know
Your Majesty made these dishes.
Because of me,
all of you had to leave home
and come all the way
to the Central Plains.
You can't even
eat hometown food here.
I'm sorry about that.
I made these dishes
as my apology to you all.
- Thank you, Your Majesty.
I'm not an emperor today,
but a kid.
You're my elders.
Please make yourselves at home.
Please sit down.
Please.
- Yes.
- Yes, Your Majesty.
Mr. Huhe.
What do you think of the dishes?
Good.
Especially the grilled silkworms
taste as good
as what Lady Xiezu cooked.
Do you all remember?
That year,
we ventured deep into the enemy's camp,
ran out of food
and were seriously injured.
But we survived
on the silkworms raised
by Lady Xiezu.
Indeed.
The queen was merciful.
Back then,
each soldier
serving the Great Emperor
owed Her Highness.
- Yes, indeed.
- Yes.
I heard a lot about you
from my grandmother.
In the past, Xiyan's territory
covered the North and Xi Jiang.
Now the territory is vast,
stretching from Yuyuan in the west
to the Donghai Sea,
governing most of Dahuang.
It all thanks to
your deeds of valor in battle.
You insist on staying
in the Central Plains.
I thought
you were captivated
by its prosperity
and forgot the past hardships.
I've decided to stay here
not because I've forgotten the past.
I'm walking
the same path my grandparents took,
leading the Xiyan clans
to make Xiyan thrive
and give people a peaceful life.
I've never forgotten your contributions
to the country.
My men asked around.
It is true.
To please those old folks,
(Xiyan Shiran)
Cang Xuan shamelessly cooked for them.
He humiliated himself.
Cang Xuan is scheming.
He might have
won over those old folks
by a carrot-and-stick approach.
Brother.
We can no longer stay
in the Central Plains.
Instead of enduring
Cang Xuan's arrogance,
why not
fight him together?
While the old clans still support us,
take the chance
to oppose the capital relocation
and lead them back to Xiyan.
Just let Cang Xuan stay here
and be the king.
Plus,
you can take this chance
to make yourself king
in Xiyan Town.
Brother.
It's a rare opportunity.
If Cang Xuan
wins over the clans
and secures his throne,
I'm afraid
we will have no more chances.
Okay.
Shiran.
You invite the leaders
of each clan to come
and discuss matters.
Let's return to Xiyan Town together.
Yes.
When you have time,
we'll go to Baili
to remove the poisonous bug.
Rest assured.
After that,
I will still keep my promise
to you.
Alright.
When I have time.
I'll deliver the pills to you
every three months.
I have to go.
Join me for a meal.
Sorry, but I don't have time.
You better not
refuse my invitation.
But now you are Fangfeng Bei.
So who were you
talking to just now?
Alright.
General Xiang Liu.
What kind of meat is this?
It smells so good.
Donkey meat.
In Dahuang,
no one is better at cooking donkey meat
than him.
What a surprise.
It's been centuries.
You came with a friend
for the first time.
(Mr. Lirong)
A girl, even.
It's made especially for you.
Try it.
Thank you.
A while ago,
two more brothers left us.
Those who followed Chi...
Followed the general
have almost all died.
Every man will die
sooner or later.
You are right.
Maybe one day,
you and I will die.
Look at you.
When she's around you,
you don't even dare
to approach her.
Now,
she left with another man.
And it makes you upset.
What can I do even if I approach her?
What a small world, Jing.
What do you say?
What's your name, young lady?
Young lady.
Fangfeng Bei
is as bad
as that old stallholder.
He's not the right one.
Why not
be with my buddy?
My buddy
was set up
by a woman
and got her pregnant.
However,
that's not
an unforgivable mistake, right?
Lirong Chang!
Just think about it.
He made a mistake.
So he won't make the same mistake
again.
After getting married, you'll have less
to worry about.
Are you done?
No.
Young lady.
To be honest,
Fangfeng Bei
can't give you a stable life.
Though Tushan Jing made a mistake,
he's still better than Fangfeng Bei.
I'm already engaged.
He is not my fiancé.
So, please.
Stop belittling others.
Engaged?
To whom?
Who dares to take my buddy's woman?
Tell me his name.
I'll talk to him right now.
If he doesn't call it off,
I'll break his legs.
Chishui Fenglong.
Go talk to him.
Feng...
You are Fenglong's fiancée?
So,
you are
Princess of Haoling?
King of Xiyan's sister?
You are quite polite to him.
What he said is true.
I'm not a good man
for any woman.
You know it.
You're the daughter of Princess General?
And your father?
I am the Princess of Haoling.
So, my father is the King of Haoling.
♪Rain keeps pouring♪
♪Grass grows tall♪
♪Snow covers all♪
♪Be it sere or in its prime,
it surrounds the bones of loyal men♪
Stop singing. You're drunk.
♪Chenrong's men never yield♪
Alright, you're drunk.
I'm not drunk.
♪Rain keeps pouring♪
Stop it.
♪Grass grows tall♪
♪Snow covers all♪
Well,
he can't hold his liquor.
Yet he likes to drink.
Once he gets drunk,
he loves to sing random folk songs.
Well,
he lost one arm.
And he's crippled.
He's practically disabled.
We're here for a meal.
Once I leave this place,
I will remember nothing.
Are you done?
Let's go if you are.
We have to go.
Take your time.
Lirong Chang knows your identity.
That one-armed old man
is his uncle.
He was once a general under Chi Chen.
He took part in the battle of Jizhou?
His arm was lost
in the battle of Jizhou.
Today,
things changed in the Central Plains.
Be careful.
Are you worried about my safety?
What are you thinking?
I'm just casually reminding you.
I think
you should worry about yourself.
Myself?
What about me?
I'm pretty good.
Yes.
You're doing so well.
That's why you gamble alone
at the casino.
Why is it so hard
to find a companion?
It's not that hard.
Yet it's indeed hard to find someone
with similar tastes,
who treats you sincerely
and makes your life interesting.
Can a person not forget someone
for a lifetime?
That depends on who it is.
If you're talking
about Tushan Jing,
I think it's very possible.
Are you saying he can't forget me?
Or I can't forget him?
It's up to you.
Anyway, there are plenty of good men.
There are many good men.
But,
a few of them will stay true
to you.
What do you mean by that?
Do you think
I shouldn't marry Chishui Fenglong?
I don't mean anything.
You're asking me.
I just honestly expressed my opinion.
So,
if I don't marry him,
who else should I marry?
You're asking me?
How would I know?
Anyway, the man I marry
can't have a family
or be my brother's enemy.
♪Eyes like stars♪
Xiaoyao.
♪Being lovesick♪
♪Having got the love poisonous bug♪
♪Carved in my bones and heart♪
That's about as far as I can get you.
Ahead of you...
♪Waiting for snow♪
Is your world.
♪Waiting for destiny's favor♪
♪Waiting for you a lifetime♪
♪Yearning surpasses time♪
♪Waiting brings no bloom♪
Xiaoyao.
What are you looking at?
Why are you ignoring me?
Nothing.
Just a passerby in my life.
That's all.
After all, we can't travel
together.
♪The tones of tenderness♪
Let's go.
Go.
♪Scenes unfurl within myself♪
♪It's the way back. It's the way home♪
♪Life is like dancing in the snow♪
♪It's loneliness♪
How is it?
Have the guests arrived?
The clan leaders sent people to say
that they were not available
and couldn't make it.
None of them can come?
Do you know why?
The leader of the Shangyang clan
happens to have a banquet today.
They have all gone to his banquet.
He holds a banquet too?
He did it on purpose.
He is deliberately against me.
(Your Majesty.)
Establish a capital,
and the country will be stable.
Relocating the capital
must be done quickly.
Please make a decision, Your Majesty.
Your Majesty.
Now, the territory of Xiyan is vast.
And Zhiyi is in the heart of it
and more suitable to be the capital.
I also agree to move the capital.
Agreed.
Move the Zhiyi,
and it'll facilitate governance.
Agreed.
- Agreed.
I object.
Yu Jiang.
Yes?
I command you
to oversee the matter
of relocating the capital.
(Yu Jiang)
Yes, Your Majesty.
- Your Majesty is wise.
Uncles.
Do you have any problems?
- Your Majesty is wise.
You handled it very well
in the matter of relocating the capital.
Thank you
for leaving the Shangyang clan
and the others
to me.
If it weren't for them,
things wouldn't have gone so smoothly.
I give them to you.
But it's your decision
on how to use them.
No need to think of me.
Yes, I see.
The emperor wields power
and is also driven by power.
You chose this path
yourself.
There is no way back.
And you cannot
even stop.
You have to push forward.
Yes.
I understand.
Father.
I long for the homeland.
I have already told His Majesty
we're going to return to Xiyan Mountain.
Have you decided?
I originally couldn't admit defeat.
But Cang Xuan has been recognized.
We will humiliate ourselves
if we don't give up.
It's better to let it go
and enjoy my life.
At least, I can end well.
Okay.
It's not too late for you
to figure it out.
As long as the two of you
don't do anything wilder,
Cang Xuan
will not give you a hard time.
In the future,
I can't accompany you.
Father, please take care of your health.
Rise.
- I take my leave.
Xie.
Our grandson has done very well,
better than I expected.
He convinced them with emotion
and won them over with benefits.
It's a carrot-and-stick approach.
Originally,
I thought
my two good-for-nothing sons
would be sacrificed for the country.
Unexpectedly,
things end
without bloodshed.
The two of them
end up well.
I feel happy today.
Have a drink with me.
Come on.
Greetings, Your Majesty.
No need for that.
I made some pastries
that you like.
His Majesty can't eat unexpected food.
I must do poison testing,
and then someone tastes it.
You don't have to.
Thank you, anyway.
I haven't done enough
for you yet.
These days,
you've been on the line.
It's life and death.
I've also been anxious,
fidgeting about.
But I couldn't help.
I could only remind
myself of the promise we made.
The promise?
Has Your Majesty forgotten?
We promised
that whatever happened,
I would be with you.
Fortunately, Your Majesty was blessed
and ascended the throne smoothly.
Finally,
I felt relieved.
Whatever happens,
you'll be with me?
Yes, I only have an eye for you.
I'll be with you whatever happens.
(The memorial from Chishui Fenglong)
(The emperor wields power)
(and is also driven by power.)
(You chose this path yourself.)
(There is no way back.)
(And you cannot)
(even stop.)
(You have to push forward.)
Your Majesty?
I understand.
Your Majesty.
The poison testing?
No need.
It tastes good.
If you like it,
I will make more.
Here's one thing
I want you to do.
I'm listening, Grandfather.
Can you find a way
to persuade Xiang Liu to surrender?
Persuading Xiang Liu to surrender?
It's difficult.
It's very difficult.
For centuries,
Deyan and Chenrong Yi
have both tried.
But they were rejected.
Still, I hope
you will have a try.
If it's accomplished,
it'll good to the country
and the people.
I will appoint someone
clever and capable
to deal with this matter
and make every effort to do it.
Good.
This is not a place
for Chief Lirong.
I actually think
I'm the right person to be here.
(Xiang Liu)
Go ahead.
What is it?
His Majesty asked me
to persuade you to surrender.
Do you know the fate
of the last person
who did the same thing?
Of course, I do.
But I have to come.
As an envoy of Xiyan,
I'm here to persuade you to surrender.
But as your friend,
I advise you spare yourself.
Spare myself?
I know.
You helped Hong Jiang
to repay his kindness.
I don't think
you'll change sides and serve Xiyan.
However,
you can take this opportunity to secede.
I secede?
You have already served Hong Jiang
for centuries.
No matter what,
you don't owe him now.
Why not take this chance
to unload this heavy burden?
And you can live in seclusion
or wander the world.
Do whatever you want.
Even if you meet someone you like,
you can marry her, have children,
and spend your life with her.
It's a joyful life.
Grandpa.
Grandpa, let me help you.
Good kid.
Let's go.
I'll make you something tasty.
Granny, I'll support you.
Okay, let's go.
Come on.
(Rejuvenation Hall, Qingshui Town)
Shall we go back to eat?
If you have any requests,
just let me know.
The King of Xiyan will try
to fulfill you.
No need.
Go back.
You stubborn nine-headed demon.
What is it that you really want?
You know what happened
to Chi Chen.
He staked his life
for the Central Plains.
And now?
No one remembers him.
Haven't you seen
the kind of life
my uncle is living?
This is a path doomed to failure.
What are you holding on to?
The mountains and rivers remain,
but the old friends are gone.
♪When my blood splatters
on your clothes♪
♪It looks like peach blossoms♪
♪As long as you can see me♪
(Chi Chen)
♪Oh, yeah♪
♪Please cut out my heart♪
General!
♪Let my blood flood the wilderness♪
This is General Chi Chen's love song
for his wife.
Where did you hear it?
Baili.
Did the girl who came with you
put the poisonous bug in you?
Why?
You should not see her anymore.
Go to Baili.
Wu King can remove it from you.
The Baili people are eccentric.
They don't like to deal with strangers.
Why will the Wu King
help a stranger?
He will.
As long as he sees that girl,
he will definitely help you.
That girl is...
What?
Never mind.
Great Princess of Haoling
and Chi Chen,
what exactly is their relationship?
It will not work out.
You better let her go.
Your positions are different.
Don't end up like the general.
He was in love with a woman
but had to fight her to the death
on the battlefield.
You two
have different positions.
It's doomed to have no good outcome.
You better stop.
Let her go.
Don't see her again.
Stop it.
Don't worry.
She said
I couldn't appear in her dreams.
The person she likes
is not me.
Your Highness.
The weather is nice.
How about archery practice?
I don't want to.
How about making pills?
His Majesty has sent rare herbs
to you.
Not interested.
(Miao Pu, Shan Hu)
How about playing the zither?
Snacks?
Or have a few drinks?
Not interested.
Xiaoyao.
What's wrong?
You've been listless recently.
Not at all.
Everything is going well.
How about you?
Are you happy?
Why?
Why ask that all of a sudden?
Miao Pu said
you always sat late into the night.
I thought you would get better
after a while.
But you seem more and more upset.
I'm very worried about you.
Maybe it's because you're the King now,
and I have no pressure.
So my life
is not as disciplined as before.
Is that really so?
Don't look at me like that.
I thought that once I was enthroned,
I could give you
what I couldn't before
and make your life better than before.
But you are not happy now.
Did I do something wrong?
It's not your fault.
It's my problem.
You tell me
what goes wrong.
Recently,
I've been thinking about Qingshui Town
and the days
we spent in the Zhaoyun Hall.
I cherish those good times.
But I don't like indulging
in the past.
Even if the past was beautiful,
I have to move on.
The past is the past.
But I don't know what's wrong with me.
I just
always think of Shiqi.
I don't know
why I am so weak.
I don't like who I am now.
Xiaoyao.
You are not alone now.
I'm here for you. You can cry.
You can be weak.
It's okay.
In the past,
if I became weak
when facing something,
I would die.
So, I told myself
I couldn't be weak.
I just don't understand.
I've gone through so much pain
before.
Why do I
feel so heartbroken now?
Just a man, right?
Why do you
look even more upset than me?
Don't worry.
Time heals all wounds.
Many years ago, I knew
that emotional wounds are hard to heal.
So, many years later,
I can't forgive my mother
for killing herself before my eyes.
No matter how much I cried and begged,
she still left me.
Physical wounds can heal.
I believe
there must be a way
to heal emotional wounds as well.
I believe it too.
It's just I can't forgive my mother.
But now, with your companionship,
the pain of losing her
has long gone.
The happiness now
can heal past wounds.
Are you encouraging me
to start a new relationship?
I hope someone
can heal the pain
Tushan Jing caused you.
And someone else will make you
feel valued,
cherished,
and adored.
And no matter what,
he will never abandon you.
Well,
I've been unlucky since childhood.
I don't think
I'll meet someone like that.
You will.
Xiaoyao.
(If I had known)
(you would cry)
(over Tushan Jing,)
(even if I wanted the help)
(of the Tushan Family,)
(I couldn't have given him the chance
to get close to you.)
(Now I hate Tushan Jing.)
(But I hate myself even more.)
(Tushan)
♪Looking back on my old days♪
♪I was unruffled
with no sorrow and soreness♪
♪In my chaotic life,
I failed to meet your gaze♪
♪Only emptiness remained♪
♪Enduring all things in my life♪
♪I valued all but indifferent
to wealth and fame♪
♪Basking in the sun,
I couldn't feel your sunlight♪
♪All I feel is a painful heat wave♪
♪All things are dim,
while only your eyes shine bright♪
♪I'll follow my heart
and go to chase the sun far away♪
♪Everything seems sad,
while only your brows raise in delight♪
♪I'm waiting for you
to enjoy the scenery at night♪
♪You came with wind and rain,
while left with my four seasons♪
♪All is bleak without you♪
♪It began like a tornado,
and went away leaving only dust♪
♪Without you,
even the most beautiful world is a mess♪