Boy!
The tide is on the turn.
I'm not warning you again!
Ships! There!
Danes...
The devil's turds.
- Are they traders?
- No!
They come as Vikings!
We go!
Go! Go!
Where's my son?
Uhtred, take half a dozen
men and ride to the river.
There are pagans
there, you watch them,
- see how many they are.
- Course, Father.
Do nothing more, you understand?
- Yes, Father.
- Osbert, what is it?
- Ships. I saw them first from the beach.
- What ships?
Danes! There
heading for the river.
Oh, God and his saints
preserve us, they have no soul.
- We must pray.
- We must act.
Uhtred. Do not fight
them, not a single one.
- And be back by nightfall.
- Yes, Father.
They are sent by God
to punish us, for our sins.
Our sins be damned,
they are here to support
the Viking army in Eoferwic.
- Aelfric!
- You must instruct the priest
to pray for our deliverance.
- Aelfric!
- Lord?
Get them inside.
We take in as many
women and elders as we can.
The rest go to higher
ground and out of sight.
Send word to rouse the country. I
want every man inside this fortress.
And every man must
be prepared to die.
Port side ready to row.
Starboard side ready to row.
Father.
Let's go.
Taste.
Ah, fresh sweet water.
Yes. What else do you see?
I see a clear river, with
fish as big as a man's leg.
I see a forest alive with meat.
But more than that I see
a place to grow fat and old.
Horses.
Yeah, and I see spies,
shitting themselves.
Yeah!
We'll meet sword with sword!
You're pagans! We have
the greater god on our side.
Kjartan. I think we should
teach this boy a lesson.
Taking her in.
At speed!
Why do I leave the villages
unprotected and bring the men inside?
Is that your question?
A village can be rebuilt,
a warrior can die only once.
The Danes are maybe
heading south to Eoferwic,
but they will kill whoever
they can on the way.
Now, go find the priest.
Yes, Father.
Come in, Osbert, don't
skulk in the shadows.
He, er, wants to
know if you're ready.
Almost.
Do you know what
I am tasked with?
Erm, a letter?
A response to a letter,
this letter. From King Aella,
asking your father for
his support, his army,
to help recapture
the city of Eoferwic.
This is why it's important for
you to be able to read and write.
Father can't read nor write.
Yeah, well, for your
father it's too late.
King Aella could have
sent a man on horseback.
Yeah, but who's to say the man
on horseback speaks the truth?
Or has remembered
the true message?
What these letters will
represent is history, facts...
Your father is informing
King Aella, and King Osbert,
he will be alongside
their armies at Eoferwic.
And the mark of Bebbanburg
will guarantee the truth of it.
Why do we fight for Eoferwic?
Well, we fight for Eoferwic because
we do not wish to see England,
piece by piece, become Daneland.
I heard it said that
we were pagans once,
that Woden and
Odin are the same.
We saw the error of our
ways and we looked to Rome.
I heard the pagans
had fierce gods of war.
Well, we are right
and they are mistaken.
Osbert, we are blessed.
I should make you swear
on St Cuthbert's comb
never to mention the
likes of Woden again.
But what if I had a
hound called Woden?
What if I didn't, what
would you do then?
- You have not.
- What would you do then?
What if you had
a pig called Thor?
Come, let's go see
your father. Come.
A pig called Thor.
Is it really St Cuthbert's comb?
Of course it's St Cuthbert's comb, and his
holy hair lies in the teeth of that comb.
Where was your father last?
He was humping the servant girl.
- That is a lie, Osbert.
- No.
Are you never
gonna tire of teasing?
Nope.
Horsemen approaching!
He rides Uhtred's horse.
Osbert.
No. No!
Bury what's left of him.
Osbert. Come on.
Remind me of the last
words I spoke to him.
You told him to watch and do not fight,
we have no idea of the circumstance...
- Do not fight means do not fight.
- He was young.
There was no fight to
be had until Eoferwic.
You wanted to see
Osbert, My Lord.
You...
You are now called Uhtred.
Uhtred, son of Uhtred.
You have your stone, the amber?
Yes, Father.
The priest will show you
your history, the parchments.
Make him understand who he is.
Lord, I, I should like
to baptise him again.
Well, if he arrives at
Heaven's gate as Uhtred,
they may wonder what's
happened to Osbert.
Do what you must,
but do as I ask.
Lord.
We were kings here once, boy.
Kings of all the land between
the Rivers Tuede and Tine.
And we should be kings again.
Yes we should, but it doesn't
matter what they call us,
so long as they obey.
Our ancestors took this land,
and it has been strengthened
with our blood and bone.
And now you are the new heir
of Bebbanburg, do you hear me?
And you will die
for it if needed.
Yes, Father.
And I will give you the head
of the man who killed Uhtred.
No, you are Uhtred!
Have you not been
listening to me?
Do not tell me what it is you
will do, you are just a pup!
You will give me nothing, you
will watch and you will learn!
Put him in the water before his
mother's tongue gives me grief.
She's not my mother.
Will you take him with you
to battle to watch and learn?
- He's old enough.
- I need you to choose 30 men
and remain here at Bebbanburg.
Protect the boy, he is the heir.
Thirty will hold and is few enough
to feed. Will you do this for me?
I'd rather be with
you at Eoferwic,
- but I'll do as you ask.
- Thank you.
Come on quickly,
up there, go on.
Hurry, please.
Heavenly Father,
receive your servant
Uhtred into the
Holy Kind of Saints
and into the ranks of
the most bright angels.
Let your holy waters cleanse him
and make and him
worthy of your blessing,
make him your
instrument and your rod.
Let him realise the
significance of the written word
so he may learn of your glory
and in turn may
spread your word.
- Beo...
- Let him grow in wisdom
and in respect.
- Beo...
- So he may lead in a Godly manner.
Beocca, he's cleansed.
Amen.
Uhtred, son of
Uhtred of Bebbanburg,
welcome to the Christian world.
Behold your people
and your lands.
Where are the
people? The soldiers?
On the road to Eoferwic,
led by your father,
where he will join the other
two kings of Northumbria.
Without me?
You are to remain at
Bebbanburg with your kindly uncle.
I am sworn to keep you
safe. Should you wish to fight
- we can always arm-wrestle.
- Where's the priest?
With your father. Eat.
You have work to do,
Uhtred, in the stables.
Thankfully, we've
been left horses.
- You should eat.
- I'm not hungry.
We have work to do,
horse shit to shovel.
Come and find me
when you've finished.
Scallion...
If my brother falls in battle,
the boy must fall.
All this way and
no reception party.
- Earl Ragnar.
- Guthrum.
- How are you?
- I'm fine, I'm hungry.
- And your boy?
- He's coming.
- Ragnar.
- Ubba, I brought men and horses.
Good to see you. Are you well?
You made a gift of
his own son's head?
How did this lord react?
He did nothing.
He brought his warriors into
the fortress, kept them inside.
It was not cowardice.
Restraint.
He's saving his men.
That man is Uhtred.
One of the three kings of
Northumbria. A warrior king.
The other two are fools, they'd
rather be here fighting each other.
- This is true?
- King Aella and King Osbert,
they, er, both lay
claim to Eoferwic.
They have the
strangest of names.
So, when do we fight?
Soon, I hope.
I'm still to decide.
Fools or not, they
have three armies,
- they have numbers. EARL
RAGNAR: But are divided.
Three kings, but only one
who can lead them, this Uhtred.
And we kill him and
Northumbria is ours,
all of it.
Listen to him, listen to the
boy, he reminds me of me.
Yeah, when you were younger.
Of course when I was
younger. He's just a boy.
- Just saying. EARL
RAGNAR: Ubba.
Did you say I was old?
Storri... I'm not getting old.
- No.
Ubba, I have seen the
land outside the city.
I have a plan in
mind, a good plan.
And my son would like
to wet his sword with you.
So do we fight?
Storri?
The signs are good.
Only this morning I saw a
raven fly towards the Saxon camp
and he was asking me
to follow, I'm sure of it.
Mmm.
Then we fight.
What kind of hell is this?
It's a pagan's hell.
We out number them.
No, there are more,
there must be...
Nothing changes, we
attack with half our number,
the second half to follow once
we have the measure of them.
They have conceded
to higher ground.
Kingaler, yours and Lord Uhtred's
army will attack in the first wave.
Prepare! Prepare!
Shield!
No. No, not without me.
Come nightfall, we'll
be rid of this plague!
And counting our
share of the plunder!
My shield.
Kill them all!
The wall is holding.
Go! Hands below
your shield and drive!
Drive on!
Ease.
Ease!
Push. Keep
pushing! It's working!
Drive them!
They're tiring, they
can't fight back.
We're winning,
look! We're winning...
Not yet!
Dear God, no.
Shield!
Wall!
Dear God of infinite
mercy, not this.
Kill them all!
Legs! Legs! Protect your legs!
Lift up your sword and spare these
men of England who fight in your name.
Let the heathen's hearts
crumble and wither.
Restore your power upon
these men of England,
so they can glorify your name
with the blood of the devils.
Have mercy now, Lord.
Do not forsake us, do
not forsake England.
Follow me! Follow me!
Take him!
Close the sealed wall,
close the wall and take him!
No!
He's like a wasp.
The wasp has lost its sting.
- Yeah.
Are you sure he's a
Saxon? He fights like a Dane.
Yeah.
Leave her.
She is to live.
Some of these young
ones can come in useful.
Father, there's
the boy I spoke of.
The one who almost killed you?
You're leaving him with me?
I've never seen a man
get the better of you yet.
Cut me some chicken.
Careful, the blade is sharp.
It can kill a man.
The chicken is on your platter.
- Hmm.
- Have you always been blind?
Oh, I see enough.
So who have they
been killing below?
Prisoners.
Just now, a king.
Did he die well?
No.
Then he shouldn't
have been king.
Tell me,
who sits in the
middle of the hall?
Is it a big man and a small man?
Yes and a grey man
sits in between them.
If you get to live, you should
beware of the big man, Ubba.
My advice for you is
to never cross Ubba
and never, never fight him.
If I get to live?
He listens to no
one but the gods.
Men who take their orders
from the gods are unpredictable.
What did you mean,
when you said if I get to live?
You're my prisoner.
The grey man will be Egbert,
he's a Saxon ealdorman.
He has pledged allegiance
and now he calls himself king.
He is king of nothing.
Soon, all of the kings in
England shall be kings of nothing.
Northumbria's ours.
Mercia will soon by ours.
Then East Anglia, Cornwallum,
and then the greatest prize
is the last Kingdom,
- Wessex.
- I've heard of Wessex.
Anything will grow in Wessex.
Tell me your name.
Uhtred.
I am the Ealdorman
of Bebbanburg.
You are?
I am, I own lands to the north.
How long have you been
an ealdorman of these lands?
Your father chose to fight us.
And is now... Dead.
He, he... He was not fond of me.
I now understand why
my son spared you,
Uhtred of Bebbanburg.
You are a warrior.
Have some ale.
Drink it,
lots of it.
Here, take it up there.
I'm thinking of
keeping them both,
the boy and the girl,
they can help your mother.
- Disagree?
- No.
But we did kill his father.
And if he is an ealdorman,
we could sell him for a ransom.
Perhaps.
Brida, be careful
not to spill the water,
you'll turn the floor to mud.
Uhtred, wood
needs to be chopped.
Brida, you can do the goats.
Will there be time
for Uhtred to play?
Only when work is done.
I don't like our daughter
having to play with the slaves.
They're only children.
They have a place.
Grumpy.
- My horse.
- Hey, Ragnar Ragnarson.
Hey, Uhtred of wherever.
How about you teach
me how to use a sword?
We Don't teach
slaves how to fight.
That tongue of yours
will be your death, boy.
Now, get back to work.
What does the play involve?
We built a hall in the gorge.
I'm the mistress and
Uhtred is a warrior.
Not a servant?
It is a game.
A wolf! Uhtred.
That's it, a wolf.
Boar! Watch out!
I saw it, its sharp
teeth and yellow eyes.
Don't let the wolves
get to me, Uhtred.
- Use the fire to keep them away.
- I see them.
They are as big as
Ubba and smell worse.
Did you see that?
Uhtred?
Stay up there.
Look.
Uhtred, what is happening?
Stay up there, Thyra.
It's Sven, he won't hurt you.
But he'll kill us.
He'll kill us! Run!
That was a real sword.
I saw it.
- Uhtred! Uhtred!
- Thyra!
What's this?
You been fighting again?
Yes.
With Sven?
Kjartan's son?
Yes.
- Uhtred, he's much bigger than you.
- He's a turd.
Why do you say that?
RAVN: Who started it?
Who began the fight?
I began the fight.
For no other reason
than that he's a turd?
Danes have murdered for less.
Uhtred, that's enough.
- Do you want to be sold, boy?
- I wish to eat.
- Speak up!
You want to eat?
You know what?
I say you starve.
Fighting is expected,
disobedience is not.
Sven began the fight.
Kjartan!
Earl Ragnar, let me first
say, he's a, he's a good boy.
He brought this sword onto my
land. I will have words with him.
In time he'll serve on
your ship. He... He...
- He has offended me.
- He will honour you
- and he meant no harm, Lord.
- He meant no harm?
He looked at my
daughter's nakedness.
And he was punished.
Your Saxon slave cut him.
Shall I make a
square of branches?
Are you gonna fight me
for your son or fetch him?
Sven.
Come out here.
- Tell him what you have to say.
- I'm sorry.
- He can't hear you.
- I'm sorry, Lord.
For what I did.
You laid hands on my daughter.
You stripped her naked.
- Half naked, Lord.
- He is at an age, Lord.
Is this true? Half naked?
Yes, Lord.
Then I shall only
take his one eye.
No, no, please.
Kjartan, you are
banished from my land.
I have something for you.
What is it?
An amulet, Thor's hammer.
Ah, but, er...
But what?
You're Christian.
Take it.
- I can't.
- Don't you want it?
I, I do want it.
- Take it.
- I'm trying.
- Take it. YOUNG RAGNAR:
I don't think he wants it.
I, I do want it.
No, I don't think so.
Thank you.
Tell me about Denmark.
Your home.
What can I say about Denmark?
It's wet.
And harsh.
Er, the ground is so flat
and sandy, you
can't grow a fart.
Which is why we're
here in England,
to grow, and why
Young Ragnar will
soon be going for Ireland.
You leave to fight?
To make my wealth.
If you want land or
silver, you have to take it.
You made me
proud today,
Uhtred.
You made me proud.
I don't know you, you don't have
the appearance of a messenger.
And Ubba's
payment's not yet due.
No, Lord, I was a ship's master.
Ah, well I have no ships,
I need no ship's master.
I have news that
you will want to hear.
- Well?
- I would want something in return, Lord.
Not now, not quite.
But perhaps we could
continue to help each other.
Perhaps.
Two days south of here.
This little rat with the
man I used to serve,
until he banished me.
He has a slave,
treats him well.
But this is a slave you are
entitled to buy back if you wish to.
Buy back?
It's your nephew Uhtred, Lord.
He lives.
What if I'm against
being ransomed?
Your family has discovered
that you're still alive
and they wish for
you to be returned,
but they must pay.
Pay Ragnar?
Ubba takes more than half.
It's normal.
But I have no family.
Keep them over there,
tether the horses...
Scallion, here.
Uhtred.
They treating you well?
I am fed, yes.
Good, good. That is all we ask.
And what is this around
your neck, some symbol?
Oh this. They make me wear it.
May I see it?
Look, I will speak plainly,
your uncle will kill you.
Right, you cannot go back to
Bebbanburg, you must escape.
He wants to be the ealdorman.
He wants to be the king, in fact,
like the pathetic Egbert over there.
A puppet king for
his Danish masters.
You should go to Wessex.
King Aethelred, real King Aethelred
and his brother the Prince Alfred,
they're good men,
good Christian men.
That is enough
whispering in his ear, priest.
- Uhtred.
- One more word
and I'll have your
ball-bag for a purse.
I'll meet you there.
That will not be necessary.
What did he say?
He... He asked if you
were treating me well.
How much? RAVN: 300.
That is a ridiculous amount.
How can a boy be worth
300 pieces of silver?
Because I say so,
because he is a
lord, an ealdorman.
He is a boy. I am the
Ealdorman of Bebbanburg.
I carry the seal and the banner.
That seal is my father's,
which is now mine!
You will be silent.
You are for sale, nothing more.
For ransom, Lord.
- That's is what I said.
- My Lords...
I have given up land, horses.
I've offered a generous supply
of food as well as my sword.
All I ask in return is a fair
price for my only nephew.
What would you
say is a fair price?
I will offer 100
pieces of silver.
200.
My allegiance and 100
pieces is surely a fair price.
It is not.
I will give 120 pieces
of silver for the boy.
Not enough.
Very well, 200 pieces.
I agree to your terms.
- The boy's sold to Earl Ragnar.
- What?
- Ransomed, Lord.
- That's what I said.
So the matter is closed.
My Lords, I have
come a long way.
I have offered my allegiance.
Which is why you
are allowed to breathe.
If you have an argument,
it's with me now.
If business is done,
we have ale to drink.
And King Uhtred needs to sit.
Am I not for ransom anymore?
You heard Ubba, I bought you.
I thought I might
sacrifice you to Odin.
You bought me for how much?
- Too much.
- How much is too much?
My sword's weight in silver.
I agree, I may have been robbed,
but we like you, boy.
We're going to keep you.
Does this mean I'm a Dane?
It means you're
Uhtred Ragnarson.
You're a son to me now.
Brida, not that way.
Take the goat out the side.
Next time, I promise.
- Mother, look.
- It's beautiful, it really is.
I can't believe I'm
losing you already.
I will be living
across the field.
And if he does
not treat you well,
you just come marching
back across that field.
Oh, look at this place.
Uhtred, do you like
my wedding necklace?
I do, very pretty.
He doesn't know
anything about necklaces,
you might as well ask me.
Uhtred, with me. You can
help me slaughter the goats.
I've only just washed.
The goats will be pleased.
Later you can sweep the floor.
Move over.
It's an excuse
to talk, that's all.
With Thyra to be married, maybe
it's time you got together with Brida.
There are men, good
men, asking about her.
So you have to decide what you
are to her, what you are to each other.
- Brida has her own mind.
- She has.
But I see the way
she looks at you.
She's watching the
charcoal tonight in the woods.
Take my horse and join her.
The earth will be warm.
Why not?
I just thought in order to be a
real Dane, I had to marry a Dane.
Come on.
I love you like I
love Young Ragnar.
What are you doing here?
Do you ever think
of your English life?
Who you were before
we came to Ragnar?
No.
Do you?
- I think of who I...
- Shh.
Voices.
Come on.
Men, below...
Come on, that way.
Danes. Who are they?
- This way.
- That's Kjartan.
Remember him?
And that must be Sven.
This is wrong. We
need to tell Ragnar.
They are between us and hall.
Then we go up and around,
we leave the horses and run.
In front of the door. That's it.
Ragnar, smoke!
Fire! Thyra, wake up!
Odin, wake up!
Fire!
Come on. Come on!
This way, Ravn.
Come, come quickly.
The door is blocked!
So is this one!
Be ready.
This one's open, this one's open!
Come on, follow me, this way!
This way. Take the children.
Don't go up there, wait for me!
Come, come.
Ragnar.
Close the doors. We have
Thyra, let the rest burn.
Take her with you to Valhalla.
- Yes.
- I will meet you there.
Find the silver.
Now!
They're searching
for Ragnar's wealth.
- They'll never find it.
- Search in the back.
Come on, we're leaving soon.
You thought I'd left you
to marry someone else.
But do you know
what I will do with this body?
This mouth?
I will do all I have dreamt of.
And more.
And who will call a halt?
Earl Ragnar, the
Fearless, is gone,
and with him Uhtred,
his Saxon pet,
a pile of ashes.
Anything.
Get down.
Look at that man, the Saxon.
His name's Scallion.
He works with my uncle.
He'll tell him that I'm dead.
Let him do it.
I see him with Kjartan.
Burn it to the ground.
He and your uncle,
maybe there in it together.
What makes them believe they
can do this without punishment?
They will be punished,
but not by you.
Uhtred, listen to me, we
serve Ragnar best alive,
we tell the story.
- I need to kill someone.
- No.
And I choose him.
Uhtred, no.
Come on!
The barn's over there.
The main thing is to keep
the horses together, yes.
Don't leave any weapons behind.
Who goes and who will
look in the back rooms,
don't leave anything in
there, just bring it all out.
Over here!
Right, come on.
You know who I am,
it's me you're looking for,
it's me your looking
for, you remember me?
You remember me?
There's no more.
We're going. Come on!
Bring the horses.
By right, it belongs
to Young Ragnar.
Yes.
But we spend what we
need to spend, we stay alive.
We tell the story and then what?
We find a new lord to serve.
I will not stand by and have
everything that's mine taken from me.
I'm going back.
Where?
To the beginning.
Is it Scallion? RAMPART
WATCHMAN: No, My Lord.
He looks like a Dane.
Could be one of Kjartan's men.
I am Uhtred of Bebbanburg
and I shall take what is mine!
Bebbanburg's mine!
Horses!