I will dispose of the old man.
Bless you, Silas.
Teacher.
Christ be with you.
We're at least a half-hour
to Chelsea Library.
If we're gonna help Leigh,
that's too long.
Where you going?
Getting you a library card.
Excuse me. May I sit next to you?
- Yeah, sure.
- Thank you.
That's great.
Didn't say you had a boyfriend.
Thanks.
Let's see if we can access
the database on this.
"In London lies a knight
a Pope interred."
Compounding keywords:
Knight, Pope, Grail.
Your precious treasure was
almost lost, and with it, my fortune.
Can you believe how well I did?
I even convinced the monk.
I should be in theatre.
A toast to our success, Teacher.
The end of the journey is near.
Your identity shall go
with me to the grave.
There's your problem, mate.
It's your basic linguistic coincidence.
See, keywords keep coming up
with the writings...
...of some bloke named
Alexander Pope.
"A. Pope."
Your grandfather was a genius.
Come on.
Emergency.
Which service do you require?
I know the location of two murderers
wanted by French police.
We've just had a 999 call.
Triangulation leads back
to Docklands.
Caller was male.
Claimed your two murderers...
...are hiding at an Opus Dei house.
The knight we're looking for
is Sir Isaac Newton.
His life's work produced new sciences
that incurred the wrath of the Church.
Gravity, for God sakes.
And if you choose to believe...
...he was also a Grand Master
of the Priory as well.
But if he offended
the Catholic Church...
...the Pope would be the last person
to preside over his funeral.
Well, that's where I got it wrong.
"In London lies a knight
a Pope interred."
Sir Isaac Newton's funeral
was presided over...
...by his good friend,
his colleague, Alexander Pope.
A. Pope. His first initial.
How did I miss that?
Here.
Yes. Isaac Newton's tomb.
An orb.
Yes. Which one? It's not possible
to tell if a particular orb is missing.
"An orb with Rosy flesh
and seeded womb."
Solar system. The planets.
Constellations. Signs of the zodiac.
See, our moon is missing.
The moons of Saturn and Jupiter.
They're not here.
Eyes of the cherubs themselves?
Robert. These tracks.
Look at the cane marks in the dust.
Teabing was here.
He was alone.
When the two of you
arrived at my home as you did...
...others might call it God's will.
I believed that if I had the cryptex...
...I could solve the riddle alone.
But I was unworthy.
But you...
You have a reason to be here.
You're the last remaining
guardian of the Grail.
Your grandfather
and the other sénéchaux...
...would not have lied
with dying breath...
...unless they knew
their secret was preserved.
How could you know
Saunière's last words?
Leigh.
Grail quests require sacrifice.
You are a murderer.
No. No. Robert, tell her.
When history is written,
murderers are heroes.
You self-righteous bastard!
We need to just walk away.
- No, don't. Don't.
- Walk away.
I'll do what I have to now.
Anything.
Do you understand?
So now...
...can't we all be friends again?
This way.
I'm going to put this gun down.
I only want you both to listen.
I'm listening now.
For 2000 years...
... the Church has rained oppression
and atrocity upon mankind...
... crushed passion and idea alike,
all in the name of their walking God.
Proof of Jesus' mortality can bring
an end to all that suffering...
...drive this church of lies
to its knees.
Armed police!
Drop your weapon!
Stop, Silas!
We are betrayed, my son.
The living heir must be revealed.
Jesus must be shown
for what he was.
Not miraculous, simply man.
I'm sorry.
Armed police!
Drop your weapon! Drop it! Drop it!
Put it down now! Put it down!
I am a ghost.
The dark con can be exposed.
Mankind can finally be set free,
and we can do it, Robert.
The three of us.
How is Silas?
Is he..? Is he alive?
The monk?
Bishop, how would you know
this killer's name?
Get me out of here, Fache.
Wait.
Langdon never came to you
in confession, did he?
One of your followers called you
about the crime-scene photos.
I cannot be implicated here. There are
still important works to be done.
You used me.
God uses us all.
Help me, Fache.
Take him.
- Did you get his cell phone?
- Yes, sir.
I'm going to need a trace.
Your Silas is dead.
The Priory's sacred charge...
...was to reveal the heir
at the dawn of the new millennium.
The millennium came and went
and the living heir remained hidden.
The Priory failed
in their sacred charge.
So, what choice did I have?
I sought out the enemy.
I persuaded them, the Council
of Shadows, that I was an ally.
I even asked them for money
so they would never suspect me.
Rector, I made them call me.
"Teacher."
- Why don't you and I...
- No.
Robert, no words. On your knees.
Do it.
No, I mean it. Down.
Not you. No, my dear, you...
You're my miracle, Sophie.
You're the guardian of the Grail.
All the oppression of the poor
and the powerless...
...of those of different skin,
of women.
You can put an end to all that.
You must explode the truth
onto the world.
It's your duty.
You know the answer to this riddle.
Open the cryptex...
...and I'll put down the gun.
I have no idea how.
I don't know the code.
And even if I did, I wouldn't tell you.
Like your grandfather, then.
Willing to die for your secret.
But by the way you've been
looking at your hero...
...I wonder, would you
let him die for you?
Open it, Sophie, to save his life.
- Leigh, you can't just...
- Open the cryptex.
I don't know how.
Open it or he dies.
- I swear, I don't know.
- Do it! Do it!
- Stop it!
- I don't know!
Stop it!
She can't do it, Leigh.
But give me a moment.
Robert.
What are you doing?
Please.
I'm sorry.
No!
No, Robert!
No.
Oh, the map. It's ruined.
The map is ruined.
The Grail.
It's lost.
The Grail is gone.
Only the worthy
find the Grail, Leigh.
You taught me that.
Armed police!
Drop it! Drop your weapon!
Put the gun down.
That one. The old man.
You're under arrest!
You do not have to say anything,
but it may harm your defense...
...if you do not mention,
when questioned...
...something which you
later rely on in court.
Anything you do say
will be given in evidence.
I'll have some questions for you.
Robert! Robert! Robert!
How could you do it?
How could you? Robert!
To destroy our hope of freedom.
To deny every pilgrim the chance
to kneel at the tomb of the Magdalene.
How could you?
You couldn't! You solved it.
You took the scroll out
before it broke!
You solved it. Oh, you'll find it, Robert.
You'll find it. You know what to do.
You'll find the Grail,
you'll kneel before her...
...and you'll set her free
upon the world!
That man there,
he's got the map to the Holy Grail!
There was every orb conceivable
on that tomb except one:
The orb which fell from the heavens
and inspired Newton's life's work.
Work that incurred the wrath
of the Church until his dying day.
A-P-P-L-E.
Apple.
The Holy Grail 'neath
ancient Roslin waits
The blade and chalice
guarding o'er her gates
Adorned in masters'
loving art, she lies
She rests at last
beneath the starry skies
I think I know where she's gone.
I think the Grail has gone home.
Built by the Templars themselves.
Named for the original Rose Line.
Rosslyn Chapel.
So this is it.
The gift at the end.
"The Holy Grail 'neath
ancient Roslin waits."
You never told me the joke
Saunière made of you.
What was it?
He called me a flatfoot.
A beat cop of history.
Oh, a dumb policeman...
...who just does his job
day after day, of history.
You know, his father was one.
A policeman.
Saunière said he was the most
honorable man he had ever known.
We are who we protect, I think.
What we stand up for.
Jewish...
...Christian, Egyptian...
...Masonic, pagan...
...Templar crosses...
...pyramids.
I think I've been here before.
Sophie.
A very long time ago.
Come along, Sophie.
Sophie.
Over here.
"The blade and chalice
guarding o'er her gates."
Pagan symbols for
male and female.
Fused as one.
As the pagans would have wanted.
We're about to close, I'm afraid.
We're just gonna be a moment.
Robert.
"Adorned in masters'
loving art, she lies."
"She rests at last
beneath the starry skies."
The fleur-de-lis.
She was here.
Her sarcophagus.
Mary Magdalene.
The Holy Grail herself.
She was here.
Where did she go?
Did the Church finally get her?
This is incredible. Look at this.
Look at this. These records
go back thousands of years.
They date back
to the death of Christ.
Good God, could these
really be the Grail documents?
What did he want from us?
To find her sarcophagus?
How was I ever supposed
to figure all this out?
When you and your
grandfather fought...
...was it something about your past?
How could you know that?
About how your parents died?
Sophie?
It was during primary school.
I was in his library.
Doing research.
I was trying to find out
about my family.
Sophie, where are you, princess?
I wanted to know about them.
But I couldn't find any records.
Not of their death...
...not of the accident.
I'd asked him for as long
as I could remember...
... but he would never tell me.
I told you, no.
But why can't I?
He stood over me...
...and he wouldn't let me leave.
They're dead. Dead and buried.
Never look for them, Sophie.
Promise me.
Swear it!
Swear it to me!
I kept my promise.
The next week he sent me
to boarding school.
One weekend
I came home unexpectedly.
And what I saw
my grandfather doing...
Some ritual.
I was so frightened.
We hardly ever spoke again.
Do you have any memories of your
grandfather before the accident?
Before your parents were killed?
Yeah. No. I don't know.
Why?
Because I don't think
he was your grandfather.
These are my parents.
My brother.
And this is you, isn't it?
The paper says
the entire family was killed.
The mother, the father, the boy, 6...
...and the girl, 4.
But your name was never Saunière.
It's Saint-Clair.
It's one of the oldest families
in France.
It's from a line of the
Merovingian kings.
Royal blood.
I was so wrong.
Saunière didn't want you to help guard
the secret of the Holy Grail.
Sophie...
...you are the secret.
You survived the accident.
If it even was an accident.
The Priory found out.
Somehow they concealed
the fact that you were alive.
They hid you with the
Grand Master himself...
...who raised you as his own.
According to all of this...
...Princess Sophie...
...you are the heir.
The end of the bloodline.
You are the last living descendent...
...of Jesus Christ.
What is this?
Sophie?
Who are you?
There have been many names.
The keepers.
Guardians.
The Priory of Sion.
But to you, Sophie, we are friends
of the man who raised you:
Jacques Saunière.
He would have wanted you to know
that he loved you very much.
And that the Priory are here
to protect you now...
...as they have always
protected our family.
I gave you up once...
...knowing I might
never see you again.
I'm your grandmother, Sophie.
I have prayed for this moment
for a very long time.
Welcome home, child.
Hey.
She has some things
she wants to tell me.
About my family.
What will you do?
The legend will be revealed
when the heir reveals himself.
They just got the pronoun wrong.
She said when Saunière died...
...he took the location
of Mary's sarcophagus with him.
So there's no way to empirically prove
that I am related to her.
What would you do, Robert?
Okay, maybe there is no proof.
Maybe the Grail is lost forever.
But, Sophie, the only thing that
matters is what you believe.
History shows us
Jesus was an extraordinary man...
...a human inspiration. That's it.
That's all the evidence
has ever proved.
But...
...when I was a boy...
When I was down in that well
Teabing told you about...
...I thought I was going to die,
Sophie.
What I did...
...I prayed.
I prayed to Jesus to keep me alive...
...so I could see my parents again...
...so I could go to school again...
...so I could play with my dog.
Sometimes I wonder
if I wasn't alone down there.
Why does it have to be
human or divine?
Maybe human is divine.
Why couldn't Jesus
have been a father...
...and still been capable
of all those miracles?
Like turning water into wine?
Well, who knows?
His blood is your blood.
Maybe that junkie in the park
will never touch a drug again.
Maybe you healed my phobia
with your hands.
And maybe you're
a knight on a Grail quest.
Well, here's the question:
A living descendent
of Jesus Christ...
...would she destroy faith?
Or would she renew it?
So again I say, what matters
is what you believe.
Thank you.
For bringing me here.
For letting him choose you...
...Sir Robert.
You take care.
Yes.
Hey.
Nope.
Maybe I'll do better with the wine.
Godspeed.
Bloodline.
Rose Line.
"Hides beneath the Rose."
"The Holy Grail 'neath
ancient Roslin waits.
Adorned in masters'
loving art, she lies.
The blade and chalice
guarding o'er her gates.
She rests at last
beneath starry skies."